,Unnamed: 0,sentence_no,word,predicted_tag,POS_Tags
0,0,1,``,O,``
1,1,1,',O,''
2,2,1,Vyasa,B-PER,NNP
3,3,1,said,O,VBD
4,4,1,",",O,","
5,5,1,``,O,``
6,6,1,Hearing,O,VBG
7,7,1,these,O,DT
8,8,1,words,O,NNS
9,9,1,from,O,IN
10,10,1,the,O,DT
11,11,1,king,O,NN
12,12,1,(,O,","
13,13,1,Marutta,O,NNP
14,14,1,),O,","
15,15,1,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
16,16,1,was,O,VBD
17,17,1,highly,O,RB
18,18,1,gratified,O,JJ
19,19,1,",",O,","
20,20,1,and,O,CC
21,21,1,he,O,PRP
22,22,1,said,O,VBD
23,23,1,(,O,","
24,24,1,addressing,O,VBG
25,25,1,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
26,26,1,),O,","
27,27,1,",",O,","
28,28,1,',O,''
29,29,1,I,O,PRP
30,30,1,too,O,RB
31,31,1,am,O,VBP
32,32,1,quite,O,RB
33,33,1,able,O,JJ
34,34,1,to,O,TO
35,35,1,do,O,VB
36,36,1,all,O,PDT
37,37,1,that,O,DT
38,38,1,.,O,.
39,39,1,',O,''
40,40,2,Then,O,RB
41,41,2,",",O,","
42,42,2,O,O,UH
43,43,2,prince,O,NN
44,44,2,",",O,","
45,45,2,that,O,IN
46,46,2,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
47,47,2,",",O,","
48,48,2,raving,O,VBG
49,49,2,like,O,IN
50,50,2,a,O,DT
51,51,2,lunatic,O,NN
52,52,2,",",O,","
53,53,2,and,O,CC
54,54,2,repeatedly,O,RB
55,55,2,scolding,O,VBG
56,56,2,Marutta,O,NNP
57,57,2,with,O,IN
58,58,2,rude,O,JJ
59,59,2,words,O,NNS
60,60,2,",",O,","
61,61,2,again,O,RB
62,62,2,accosted,O,VBD
63,63,2,him,O,PRP
64,64,2,thus,O,RB
65,65,2,",",O,","
66,66,2,',O,''
67,67,2,I,O,PRP
68,68,2,am,O,VBP
69,69,2,afflicted,O,VBN
70,70,2,with,O,IN
71,71,2,a,O,DT
72,72,2,cerebral,O,JJ
73,73,2,disorder,O,NN
74,74,2,",",O,","
75,75,2,and,O,CC
76,76,2,",",O,","
77,77,2,I,O,PRP
78,78,2,always,O,RB
79,79,2,act,O,VBP
80,80,2,according,O,VBG
81,81,2,to,O,IN
82,82,2,the,O,DT
83,83,2,random,O,JJ
84,84,2,caprices,O,NNS
85,85,2,of,O,IN
86,86,2,my,O,PRP$
87,87,2,own,O,JJ
88,88,2,mind,O,NN
89,89,2,.,O,.
90,90,3,Why,O,WRB
91,91,3,art,O,NN
92,92,3,thou,O,PRP
93,93,3,bent,O,VB
94,94,3,upon,O,IN
95,95,3,having,O,VBG
96,96,3,this,O,DT
97,97,3,sacrifice,O,NN
98,98,3,performed,O,VBN
99,99,3,by,O,IN
100,100,3,a,O,DT
101,101,3,priest,O,NN
102,102,3,of,O,IN
103,103,3,such,O,PDT
104,104,3,a,O,DT
105,105,3,singular,O,JJ
106,106,3,disposition,O,NN
107,107,3,?,O,.
108,108,4,My,O,PRP$
109,109,4,brother,O,NN
110,110,4,is,O,VBZ
111,111,4,able,O,JJ
112,112,4,to,O,TO
113,113,4,officiate,O,VB
114,114,4,at,O,IN
115,115,4,sacrifices,O,NNS
116,116,4,",",O,","
117,117,4,and,O,CC
118,118,4,he,O,PRP
119,119,4,has,O,VBZ
120,120,4,gone,O,VBN
121,121,4,over,O,RP
122,122,4,to,O,IN
123,123,4,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
124,124,4,(,O,","
125,125,4,Indra,B-PER,NNP
126,126,4,),O,-RRB-
127,127,4,",",O,","
128,128,4,and,O,CC
129,129,4,is,O,VBZ
130,130,4,engaged,O,VBN
131,131,4,in,O,IN
132,132,4,performing,O,VBG
133,133,4,his,O,PRP$
134,134,4,sacrifices,O,NNS
135,135,4,",",O,","
136,136,4,do,O,VB
137,137,4,thou,O,DT
138,138,4,therefore,O,RB
139,139,4,have,O,VB
140,140,4,thy,O,PRP$
141,141,4,sacrifice,O,NN
142,142,4,performed,O,VBN
143,143,4,by,O,IN
144,144,4,him,O,PRP
145,145,4,.,O,.
146,146,5,My,O,PRP$
147,147,5,elder,O,JJR
148,148,5,brother,O,NN
149,149,5,has,O,VBZ
150,150,5,forcibly,O,RB
151,151,5,taken,O,VBN
152,152,5,away,O,RB
153,153,5,from,O,IN
154,154,5,me,O,PRP
155,155,5,all,O,DT
156,156,5,my,O,PRP$
157,157,5,household,O,NN
158,158,5,goods,O,NNS
159,159,5,and,O,CC
160,160,5,mystical,O,JJ
161,161,5,gods,O,NNS
162,162,5,",",O,","
163,163,5,and,O,CC
164,164,5,sacrificing,O,VBG
165,165,5,clients,O,NNS
166,166,5,",",O,","
167,167,5,and,O,CC
168,168,5,has,O,VBZ
169,169,5,now,O,RB
170,170,5,left,O,VBN
171,171,5,to,O,IN
172,172,5,me,O,PRP
173,173,5,only,O,RB
174,174,5,this,O,DT
175,175,5,physical,O,JJ
176,176,5,body,O,NN
177,177,5,of,O,IN
178,178,5,mine,O,NN
179,179,5,",",O,","
180,180,5,and,O,CC
181,181,5,",",O,","
182,182,5,O,O,UH
183,183,5,son,O,NN
184,184,5,of,O,IN
185,185,5,Avikshit,B-PER,NNP
186,186,5,",",O,","
187,187,5,as,O,IN
188,188,5,he,O,PRP
189,189,5,is,O,VBZ
190,190,5,worthy,O,JJ
191,191,5,of,O,IN
192,192,5,all,O,DT
193,193,5,respect,O,NN
194,194,5,from,O,IN
195,195,5,me,O,PRP
196,196,5,",",O,","
197,197,5,I,O,PRP
198,198,5,can,O,MD
199,199,5,not,O,RB
200,200,5,by,O,IN
201,201,5,any,O,DT
202,202,5,means,O,NNS
203,203,5,officiate,O,VB
204,204,5,at,O,IN
205,205,5,thy,O,DT
206,206,5,sacrifice,O,NN
207,207,5,",",O,","
208,208,5,unless,O,IN
209,209,5,with,O,IN
210,210,5,his,O,PRP$
211,211,5,permission,O,NN
212,212,5,.,O,.
213,213,6,Thou,O,PRP
214,214,6,must,O,MD
215,215,6,therefore,O,RB
216,216,6,go,O,VB
217,217,6,to,O,IN
218,218,6,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
219,219,6,first,O,RB
220,220,6,",",O,","
221,221,6,and,O,CC
222,222,6,taking,O,VBG
223,223,6,his,O,PRP$
224,224,6,permission,O,NN
225,225,6,thou,O,PRP
226,226,6,canst,O,MD
227,227,6,come,O,VB
228,228,6,back,O,RB
229,229,6,to,O,IN
230,230,6,me,O,PRP
231,231,6,",",O,","
232,232,6,if,O,IN
233,233,6,thou,O,PRP
234,234,6,hast,O,VBP
235,235,6,any,O,DT
236,236,6,desire,O,NN
237,237,6,to,O,TO
238,238,6,perform,O,VB
239,239,6,a,O,DT
240,240,6,sacrifice,O,NN
241,241,6,",",O,","
242,242,6,and,O,CC
243,243,6,then,O,RB
244,244,6,only,O,RB
245,245,6,shall,O,MD
246,246,6,I,O,PRP
247,247,6,officiate,O,VB
248,248,6,at,O,IN
249,249,6,thy,O,DT
250,250,6,sacrifice,O,NN
251,251,6,.,O,.
252,252,6,',O,''
253,253,7,``,O,``
254,254,7,',O,''
255,255,7,'',O,''
256,256,7,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
257,257,7,said,O,VBD
258,258,7,",",O,","
259,259,7,',O,''
260,260,7,Do,O,VB
261,261,7,thou,O,PRP
262,262,7,listen,O,VB
263,263,7,to,O,IN
264,264,7,me,O,PRP
265,265,7,",",O,","
266,266,7,O,O,UH
267,267,7,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
268,268,7,",",O,","
269,269,7,I,O,PRP
270,270,7,did,O,VBD
271,271,7,go,O,VB
272,272,7,to,O,IN
273,273,7,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
274,274,7,first,O,RB
275,275,7,",",O,","
276,276,7,but,O,CC
277,277,7,desiring,O,VBG
278,278,7,the,O,DT
279,279,7,patronage,O,NN
280,280,7,of,O,IN
281,281,7,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
282,282,7,",",O,","
283,283,7,he,O,PRP
284,284,7,did,O,VBD
285,285,7,not,O,RB
286,286,7,wish,O,VB
287,287,7,to,O,TO
288,288,7,have,O,VB
289,289,7,me,O,PRP
290,290,7,as,O,IN
291,291,7,his,O,PRP$
292,292,7,sacrificer,O,NN
293,293,7,.,O,.
294,294,8,He,O,PRP
295,295,8,said,O,VBD
296,296,8,",",O,","
297,297,8,``,O,``
298,298,8,Having,O,VBG
299,299,8,secured,O,VBN
300,300,8,the,O,DT
301,301,8,priesthood,O,NN
302,302,8,of,O,IN
303,303,8,the,O,DT
304,304,8,Immortals,O,NNPS
305,305,8,",",O,","
306,306,8,I,O,PRP
307,307,8,do,O,VBP
308,308,8,not,O,RB
309,309,8,desire,O,VB
310,310,8,to,O,TO
311,311,8,act,O,VB
312,312,8,for,O,IN
313,313,8,mortals,O,NNS
314,314,8,",",O,","
315,315,8,and,O,CC
316,316,8,",",O,","
317,317,8,I,O,PRP
318,318,8,have,O,VBP
319,319,8,been,O,VBN
320,320,8,forbidden,O,VBN
321,321,8,by,O,IN
322,322,8,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
323,323,8,(,O,:
324,324,8,Indra,B-PER,NNP
325,325,8,),O,-RRB-
326,326,8,to,O,TO
327,327,8,officiate,O,VB
328,328,8,at,O,IN
329,329,8,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
330,330,8,',O,POS
331,331,8,s,O,POS
332,332,8,sacrifice,O,NN
333,333,8,",",O,","
334,334,8,as,O,IN
335,335,8,he,O,PRP
336,336,8,told,O,VBD
337,337,8,me,O,PRP
338,338,8,that,O,IN
339,339,8,Marutta,O,NNP
340,340,8,having,O,VBG
341,341,8,become,O,VBN
342,342,8,lord,O,NN
343,343,8,of,O,IN
344,344,8,the,O,DT
345,345,8,earth,B-PLACE,NN
346,346,8,",",O,","
347,347,8,was,O,VBD
348,348,8,always,O,RB
349,349,8,filled,O,VBN
350,350,8,with,O,IN
351,351,8,a,O,DT
352,352,8,desire,O,NN
353,353,8,to,O,TO
354,354,8,rival,O,VB
355,355,8,him,O,PRP
356,356,8,.,O,.
357,357,8,'',O,''
358,358,9,And,O,CC
359,359,9,to,O,IN
360,360,9,this,O,DT
361,361,9,thy,O,PRP$
362,362,9,brother,O,NN
363,363,9,assented,O,VBD
364,364,9,by,O,IN
365,365,9,saying,O,VBG
366,366,9,to,O,IN
367,367,9,the,O,DT
368,368,9,Slayer,O,NNP
369,369,9,of,O,IN
370,370,9,Vala,B-PER,NNP
371,371,9,(,O,:
372,372,9,Indra,B-PER,NNP
373,373,9,),O,-RRB-
374,374,9,",",O,","
375,375,9,--,O,:
376,376,9,'',O,''
377,377,9,Be,O,VB
378,378,9,it,O,PRP
379,379,9,so,O,RB
380,380,9,.,O,.
381,381,9,'',O,''
382,382,10,Know,O,VBP
383,383,10,thou,O,PRP
384,384,10,",",O,","
385,385,10,O,O,UH
386,386,10,best,O,JJS
387,387,10,of,O,IN
388,388,10,ascetics,O,NNS
389,389,10,",",O,","
390,390,10,that,O,IN
391,391,10,as,O,IN
392,392,10,he,O,PRP
393,393,10,had,O,VBD
394,394,10,succeeded,O,VBN
395,395,10,in,O,IN
396,396,10,securing,O,VBG
397,397,10,the,O,DT
398,398,10,protection,O,NN
399,399,10,of,O,IN
400,400,10,the,O,DT
401,401,10,Lord,O,NNP
402,402,10,of,O,IN
403,403,10,the,O,DT
404,404,10,Celestials,O,NNPS
405,405,10,",",O,","
406,406,10,I,O,PRP
407,407,10,repaired,O,VBD
408,408,10,to,O,IN
409,409,10,him,O,PRP
410,410,10,with,O,IN
411,411,10,gratified,O,JJ
412,412,10,heart,O,NN
413,413,10,",",O,","
414,414,10,but,O,CC
415,415,10,he,O,PRP
416,416,10,did,O,VBD
417,417,10,not,O,RB
418,418,10,agree,O,VB
419,419,10,to,O,TO
420,420,10,act,O,VB
421,421,10,as,O,IN
422,422,10,my,O,PRP$
423,423,10,priest,O,NN
424,424,10,.,O,.
425,425,11,And,O,CC
426,426,11,thus,O,RB
427,427,11,repulsed,O,VBN
428,428,11,",",O,","
429,429,11,I,O,PRP
430,430,11,now,O,RB
431,431,11,desire,O,VBP
432,432,11,to,O,TO
433,433,11,spend,O,VB
434,434,11,all,O,DT
435,435,11,I,O,PRP
436,436,11,possess,O,VBP
437,437,11,",",O,","
438,438,11,to,O,TO
439,439,11,have,O,VB
440,440,11,this,O,DT
441,441,11,sacrifice,O,NN
442,442,11,performed,O,VBN
443,443,11,by,O,IN
444,444,11,thee,O,PRP
445,445,11,",",O,","
446,446,11,and,O,CC
447,447,11,to,O,TO
448,448,11,outstrip,O,VB
449,449,11,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
450,450,11,by,O,IN
451,451,11,the,O,DT
452,452,11,merit,O,NN
453,453,11,of,O,IN
454,454,11,thy,O,DT
455,455,11,good,O,JJ
456,456,11,offices,O,NNS
457,457,11,.,O,.
458,458,12,As,O,IN
459,459,12,I,O,PRP
460,460,12,have,O,VBP
461,461,12,been,O,VBN
462,462,12,repulsed,O,VBN
463,463,12,by,O,IN
464,464,12,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
465,465,12,for,O,IN
466,466,12,no,O,DT
467,467,12,fault,O,NN
468,468,12,of,O,IN
469,469,12,mine,O,NN
470,470,12,",",O,","
471,471,12,I,O,PRP
472,472,12,have,O,VBP
473,473,12,now,O,RB
474,474,12,no,O,DT
475,475,12,desire,O,NN
476,476,12,",",O,","
477,477,12,O,O,UH
478,478,12,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
479,479,12,",",O,","
480,480,12,to,O,TO
481,481,12,go,O,VB
482,482,12,to,O,IN
483,483,12,him,O,PRP
484,484,12,to,O,TO
485,485,12,seek,O,VB
486,486,12,his,O,PRP$
487,487,12,aid,O,NN
488,488,12,in,O,IN
489,489,12,this,O,DT
490,490,12,sacrifice,O,NN
491,491,12,.,O,.
492,492,12,',O,''
493,493,13,``,O,``
494,494,13,',O,''
495,495,13,'',O,''
496,496,13,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
497,497,13,said,O,VBD
498,498,13,",",O,","
499,499,13,',O,''
500,500,13,I,O,PRP
501,501,13,can,O,MD
502,502,13,certainly,O,RB
503,503,13,",",O,","
504,504,13,O,O,UH
505,505,13,king,O,NN
506,506,13,",",O,","
507,507,13,accomplish,O,VB
508,508,13,all,O,PDT
509,509,13,that,O,DT
510,510,13,thou,O,PRP
511,511,13,desirest,O,VBP
512,512,13,",",O,","
513,513,13,if,O,IN
514,514,13,only,O,RB
515,515,13,thou,O,PRP
516,516,13,agree,O,VBP
517,517,13,to,O,TO
518,518,13,do,O,VB
519,519,13,all,O,DT
520,520,13,that,O,WDT
521,521,13,I,O,PRP
522,522,13,shall,O,MD
523,523,13,ask,O,VB
524,524,13,thee,O,PRP
525,525,13,to,O,TO
526,526,13,do,O,VB
527,527,13,",",O,","
528,528,13,but,O,CC
529,529,13,I,O,PRP
530,530,13,apprehend,O,VBP
531,531,13,that,O,IN
532,532,13,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
533,533,13,and,O,CC
534,534,13,Purandara,B-PER,NNP
535,535,13,(,O,","
536,536,13,Indra,B-PER,NNP
537,537,13,),O,","
538,538,13,when,O,WRB
539,539,13,they,O,PRP
540,540,13,will,O,MD
541,541,13,learn,O,VB
542,542,13,that,O,IN
543,543,13,I,O,PRP
544,544,13,am,O,VBP
545,545,13,engaged,O,VBN
546,546,13,in,O,IN
547,547,13,performing,O,VBG
548,548,13,thy,O,PRP$
549,549,13,sacrifice,O,NN
550,550,13,",",O,","
551,551,13,will,O,MD
552,552,13,be,O,VB
553,553,13,filled,O,VBN
554,554,13,with,O,IN
555,555,13,wrath,O,NN
556,556,13,",",O,","
557,557,13,and,O,CC
558,558,13,do,O,VB
559,559,13,all,O,DT
560,560,13,they,O,PRP
561,561,13,can,O,MD
562,562,13,to,O,TO
563,563,13,injure,O,VB
564,564,13,thee,O,PRP
565,565,13,.,O,.
566,566,14,Therefore,O,RB
567,567,14,",",O,","
568,568,14,do,O,VB
569,569,14,thou,O,PRP
570,570,14,assure,O,VB
571,571,14,me,O,PRP
572,572,14,of,O,IN
573,573,14,thy,O,PRP$
574,574,14,steadfastness,O,NN
575,575,14,",",O,","
576,576,14,so,O,IN
577,577,14,as,O,IN
578,578,14,to,O,TO
579,579,14,ensure,O,VB
580,580,14,my,O,PRP$
581,581,14,coolness,O,NN
582,582,14,and,O,CC
583,583,14,constancy,O,NN
584,584,14,",",O,","
585,585,14,as,O,IN
586,586,14,otherwise,O,RB
587,587,14,",",O,","
588,588,14,if,O,IN
589,589,14,I,O,PRP
590,590,14,am,O,VBP
591,591,14,filled,O,VBN
592,592,14,with,O,IN
593,593,14,wrath,O,NN
594,594,14,against,O,IN
595,595,14,thee,O,PRP
596,596,14,",",O,","
597,597,14,I,O,PRP
598,598,14,shall,O,MD
599,599,14,reduce,O,VB
600,600,14,(,O,","
601,601,14,destroy,O,VB
602,602,14,),O,NFP
603,603,14,thee,O,NN
604,604,14,and,O,CC
605,605,14,thy,O,PRP$
606,606,14,kindred,O,NN
607,607,14,to,O,IN
608,608,14,ashes,O,NNS
609,609,14,.,O,.
610,610,14,',O,''
611,611,15,``,O,``
612,612,15,',O,''
613,613,15,'',O,''
614,614,15,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
615,615,15,said,O,VBD
616,616,15,",",O,","
617,617,15,',O,''
618,618,15,If,O,IN
619,619,15,ever,O,RB
620,620,15,I,O,PRP
621,621,15,forsake,O,VBP
622,622,15,thee,O,PRP
623,623,15,",",O,","
624,624,15,may,O,MD
625,625,15,I,O,PRP
626,626,15,never,O,RB
627,627,15,attain,O,VB
628,628,15,the,O,DT
629,629,15,blessed,O,JJ
630,630,15,regions,O,NNS
631,631,15,as,O,RB
632,632,15,long,O,RB
633,633,15,as,O,IN
634,634,15,the,O,DT
635,635,15,mountains,O,NNS
636,636,15,shall,O,MD
637,637,15,exist,O,VB
638,638,15,",",O,","
639,639,15,and,O,CC
640,640,15,the,O,DT
641,641,15,thousand-rayed,O,JJ
642,642,15,sun,O,NN
643,643,15,continue,O,VBP
644,644,15,to,O,TO
645,645,15,emit,O,VB
646,646,15,heat,O,NN
647,647,15,:,O,:
648,648,15,if,O,IN
649,649,15,I,O,PRP
650,650,15,forsake,O,VBP
651,651,15,thee,O,PRP
652,652,15,",",O,","
653,653,15,may,O,MD
654,654,15,I,O,PRP
655,655,15,never,O,RB
656,656,15,attain,O,VB
657,657,15,true,O,JJ
658,658,15,wisdom,O,NN
659,659,15,",",O,","
660,660,15,and,O,CC
661,661,15,remain,O,VB
662,662,15,for,O,IN
663,663,15,ever,O,RB
664,664,15,addicted,O,VBN
665,665,15,to,O,IN
666,666,15,worldly,O,JJ
667,667,15,(,O,","
668,668,15,material,O,JJ
669,669,15,),O,-RRB-
670,670,15,pursuits,O,NNS
671,671,15,.,O,.
672,672,15,',O,''
673,673,16,``,O,``
674,674,16,',O,''
675,675,16,'',O,''
676,676,16,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
677,677,16,said,O,VBD
678,678,16,",",O,","
679,679,16,',O,''
680,680,16,Listen,O,VB
681,681,16,",",O,","
682,682,16,O,O,UH
683,683,16,son,O,NN
684,684,16,of,O,IN
685,685,16,Avikshit,B-PER,NNP
686,686,16,",",O,","
687,687,16,excellent,O,JJ
688,688,16,as,O,IN
689,689,16,it,O,PRP
690,690,16,is,O,VBZ
691,691,16,the,O,DT
692,692,16,bent,O,NN
693,693,16,of,O,IN
694,694,16,thy,O,DT
695,695,16,mind,O,NN
696,696,16,to,O,TO
697,697,16,perform,O,VB
698,698,16,this,O,DT
699,699,16,act,O,NN
700,700,16,",",O,","
701,701,16,so,O,RB
702,702,16,too,O,RB
703,703,16,",",O,","
704,704,16,O,O,UH
705,705,16,king,O,NN
706,706,16,",",O,","
707,707,16,have,O,VBP
708,708,16,I,O,PRP
709,709,16,in,O,IN
710,710,16,my,O,PRP$
711,711,16,mind,O,NN
712,712,16,the,O,DT
713,713,16,ability,O,NN
714,714,16,to,O,TO
715,715,16,perform,O,VB
716,716,16,the,O,DT
717,717,16,sacrifice,O,NN
718,718,16,",",O,","
719,719,16,I,O,PRP
720,720,16,tell,O,VBP
721,721,16,thee,O,PRP
722,722,16,",",O,","
723,723,16,O,O,UH
724,724,16,king,O,NN
725,725,16,",",O,","
726,726,16,that,O,IN
727,727,16,thy,O,DT
728,728,16,good,O,JJ
729,729,16,things,O,NNS
730,730,16,will,O,MD
731,731,16,become,O,VB
732,732,16,imperishable,O,JJ
733,733,16,",",O,","
734,734,16,and,O,CC
735,735,16,that,O,IN
736,736,16,thou,O,PRP
737,737,16,shalt,O,MD
738,738,16,lord,O,VB
739,739,16,it,O,PRP
740,740,16,over,O,IN
741,741,16,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
742,742,16,and,O,CC
743,743,16,the,O,DT
744,744,16,Celestials,O,NNPS
745,745,16,with,O,IN
746,746,16,Gandharvas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
747,747,16,.,O,.
748,748,17,For,O,IN
749,749,17,myself,O,PRP
750,750,17,",",O,","
751,751,17,I,O,PRP
752,752,17,have,O,VBP
753,753,17,no,O,DT
754,754,17,desire,O,NN
755,755,17,to,O,TO
756,756,17,amass,O,VB
757,757,17,wealth,O,NN
758,758,17,or,O,CC
759,759,17,sacrificial,O,JJ
760,760,17,presents,O,NNS
761,761,17,",",O,","
762,762,17,I,O,PRP
763,763,17,shall,O,MD
764,764,17,only,O,RB
765,765,17,do,O,VB
766,766,17,what,O,WP
767,767,17,is,O,VBZ
768,768,17,disagreeable,O,JJ
769,769,17,to,O,IN
770,770,17,both,O,CC
771,771,17,Indra,B-PER,NNP
772,772,17,and,O,CC
773,773,17,my,O,PRP$
774,774,17,brother,O,NN
775,775,17,",",O,","
776,776,17,I,O,PRP
777,777,17,shall,O,MD
778,778,17,certainly,O,RB
779,779,17,make,O,VB
780,780,17,thee,O,PRP
781,781,17,attain,O,VB
782,782,17,equality,O,NN
783,783,17,with,O,IN
784,784,17,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
785,785,17,",",O,","
786,786,17,and,O,CC
787,787,17,I,O,PRP
788,788,17,tell,O,VBP
789,789,17,thee,O,PRP
790,790,17,truly,O,RB
791,791,17,that,O,IN
792,792,17,I,O,PRP
793,793,17,shall,O,MD
794,794,17,do,O,VB
795,795,17,what,O,WP
796,796,17,is,O,VBZ
797,797,17,agreeable,O,JJ
798,798,17,to,O,IN
799,799,17,thee,O,PRP
800,800,17,.,O,.
801,801,17,',O,''
802,802,17,'',O,''
803,803,17,',O,''
804,804,17,'',O,''
805,805,18,SECTION,O,NN
806,806,18,VIII,O,NNP
807,807,18,'',O,''
808,808,18,',O,''
809,809,18,'',O,''
810,810,18,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
811,811,18,said,O,VBD
812,812,18,",",O,","
813,813,18,',O,''
814,814,18,There,O,EX
815,815,18,is,O,VBZ
816,816,18,a,O,DT
817,817,18,peak,O,NN
818,818,18,named,O,VBN
819,819,18,Munjaban,B-PER,NNP
820,820,18,on,O,IN
821,821,18,the,O,DT
822,822,18,summits,O,NNS
823,823,18,of,O,IN
824,824,18,the,O,DT
825,825,18,Himalaya,B-PLACE,NNP
826,826,18,mountains,O,NNS
827,827,18,",",O,","
828,828,18,where,O,WRB
829,829,18,the,O,DT
830,830,18,adorable,O,JJ
831,831,18,Lord,O,NNP
832,832,18,of,O,IN
833,833,18,Uma,O,NNP
834,834,18,(,O,","
835,835,18,Mahadeva,B-PER,NNP
836,836,18,),O,-RRB-
837,837,18,is,O,VBZ
838,838,18,constantly,O,RB
839,839,18,engaged,O,VBN
840,840,18,in,O,IN
841,841,18,austere,O,JJ
842,842,18,devotional,O,JJ
843,843,18,exercises,O,NNS
844,844,18,.,O,.
845,845,19,There,O,RB
846,846,19,the,O,DT
847,847,19,mighty,O,JJ
848,848,19,and,O,CC
849,849,19,worshipful,O,JJ
850,850,19,god,O,NN
851,851,19,of,O,IN
852,852,19,great,O,JJ
853,853,19,puissance,O,NN
854,854,19,",",O,","
855,855,19,accompanied,O,VBN
856,856,19,by,O,IN
857,857,19,his,O,PRP$
858,858,19,consort,O,NN
859,859,19,Uma,B-PER,NNP
860,860,19,",",O,","
861,861,19,and,O,CC
862,862,19,armed,O,VBN
863,863,19,with,O,IN
864,864,19,his,O,PRP$
865,865,19,trident,O,NN
866,866,19,",",O,","
867,867,19,surrounded,O,VBN
868,868,19,by,O,IN
869,869,19,wild,O,JJ
870,870,19,goblins,O,NNS
871,871,19,of,O,IN
872,872,19,many,O,JJ
873,873,19,sorts,O,NNS
874,874,19,",",O,","
875,875,19,pursuing,O,VBG
876,876,19,his,O,PRP$
877,877,19,random,O,JJ
878,878,19,wish,O,NN
879,879,19,or,O,CC
880,880,19,fancy,O,NN
881,881,19,",",O,","
882,882,19,constantly,O,RB
883,883,19,resides,O,VBZ
884,884,19,in,O,IN
885,885,19,the,O,DT
886,886,19,shade,O,NN
887,887,19,of,O,IN
888,888,19,giant,O,JJ
889,889,19,forest,O,NN
890,890,19,trees,O,NNS
891,891,19,",",O,","
892,892,19,or,O,CC
893,893,19,in,O,IN
894,894,19,the,O,DT
895,895,19,caves,O,NNS
896,896,19,",",O,","
897,897,19,or,O,CC
898,898,19,on,O,IN
899,899,19,the,O,DT
900,900,19,rugged,O,JJ
901,901,19,peaks,O,NNS
902,902,19,of,O,IN
903,903,19,the,O,DT
904,904,19,great,O,JJ
905,905,19,mountain,O,NN
906,906,19,.,O,.
907,907,20,And,O,CC
908,908,20,there,O,RB
909,909,20,the,O,DT
910,910,20,Rudras,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
911,911,20,",",O,","
912,912,20,the,O,DT
913,913,20,Saddhyas,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
914,914,20,",",O,","
915,915,20,Viswedevas,O,NNP
916,916,20,",",O,","
917,917,20,the,O,DT
918,918,20,Vasus,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
919,919,20,",",O,","
920,920,20,Yama,B-PER,NNP
921,921,20,",",O,","
922,922,20,Varuna,B-PER,NNP
923,923,20,",",O,","
924,924,20,and,O,CC
925,925,20,Kuvera,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
926,926,20,with,O,IN
927,927,20,all,O,PDT
928,928,20,his,O,PRP$
929,929,20,attendants,O,NNS
930,930,20,",",O,","
931,931,20,and,O,CC
932,932,20,the,O,DT
933,933,20,spirits,O,NNS
934,934,20,and,O,CC
935,935,20,goblins,O,NNS
936,936,20,",",O,","
937,937,20,and,O,CC
938,938,20,the,O,DT
939,939,20,two,O,CD
940,940,20,Aswins,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
941,941,20,",",O,","
942,942,20,the,O,DT
943,943,20,Gandharvas,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
944,944,20,",",O,","
945,945,20,the,O,DT
946,946,20,Apsaras,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
947,947,20,",",O,","
948,948,20,the,O,DT
949,949,20,Yakshas,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
950,950,20,",",O,","
951,951,20,as,O,IN
952,952,20,also,O,RB
953,953,20,the,O,DT
954,954,20,celestial,O,JJ
955,955,20,sages,O,NNS
956,956,20,",",O,","
957,957,20,the,O,DT
958,958,20,Sun-gods,O,NNPS
959,959,20,",",O,","
960,960,20,as,O,RB
961,961,20,well,O,RB
962,962,20,as,O,IN
963,963,20,the,O,DT
964,964,20,gods,O,NNS
965,965,20,presiding,O,VBG
966,966,20,over,O,IN
967,967,20,the,O,DT
968,968,20,winds,O,NNS
969,969,20,",",O,","
970,970,20,and,O,CC
971,971,20,evil,O,JJ
972,972,20,spirits,O,NNS
973,973,20,of,O,IN
974,974,20,all,O,DT
975,975,20,sorts,O,NNS
976,976,20,",",O,","
977,977,20,worship,O,VBP
978,978,20,the,O,DT
979,979,20,high-souled,O,JJ
980,980,20,lord,O,NN
981,981,20,of,O,IN
982,982,20,Uma,B-PER,NNP
983,983,20,",",O,","
984,984,20,possessed,O,VBN
985,985,20,of,O,IN
986,986,20,diverse,O,JJ
987,987,20,characteristics,O,NNS
988,988,20,.,O,.
989,989,21,And,O,CC
990,990,21,there,O,RB
991,991,21,",",O,","
992,992,21,O,O,UH
993,993,21,king,O,NN
994,994,21,",",O,","
995,995,21,the,O,DT
996,996,21,adorable,O,JJ
997,997,21,god,O,NN
998,998,21,sports,O,NNS
999,999,21,with,O,IN
1000,1000,21,the,O,DT
1001,1001,21,wild,O,JJ
1002,1002,21,and,O,CC
1003,1003,21,playful,O,JJ
1004,1004,21,followers,O,NNS
1005,1005,21,of,O,IN
1006,1006,21,Kuvera,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1007,1007,21,",",O,","
1008,1008,21,possessed,O,VBN
1009,1009,21,of,O,IN
1010,1010,21,weird,O,JJ
1011,1011,21,and,O,CC
1012,1012,21,ghostly,O,JJ
1013,1013,21,appearances,O,NNS
1014,1014,21,.,O,.
1015,1015,22,Glowing,O,VBG
1016,1016,22,with,O,IN
1017,1017,22,its,O,PRP$
1018,1018,22,own,O,JJ
1019,1019,22,splendour,O,NN
1020,1020,22,",",O,","
1021,1021,22,that,O,DT
1022,1022,22,mountain,O,NN
1023,1023,22,looks,O,VBZ
1024,1024,22,resplendent,O,JJ
1025,1025,22,as,O,IN
1026,1026,22,the,O,DT
1027,1027,22,morning,O,NN
1028,1028,22,sun,O,NN
1029,1029,22,.,O,.
1030,1030,23,And,O,CC
1031,1031,23,no,O,DT
1032,1032,23,creature,O,NN
1033,1033,23,with,O,IN
1034,1034,23,his,O,PRP$
1035,1035,23,natural,O,JJ
1036,1036,23,eyes,O,NNS
1037,1037,23,made,O,VBN
1038,1038,23,of,O,IN
1039,1039,23,flesh,O,NN
1040,1040,23,",",O,","
1041,1041,23,can,O,MD
1042,1042,23,ever,O,RB
1043,1043,23,ascertain,O,VB
1044,1044,23,its,O,PRP$
1045,1045,23,shape,O,NN
1046,1046,23,or,O,CC
1047,1047,23,configuration,O,NN
1048,1048,23,",",O,","
1049,1049,23,and,O,CC
1050,1050,23,neither,O,CC
1051,1051,23,heat,O,NN
1052,1052,23,nor,O,CC
1053,1053,23,cold,O,JJ
1054,1054,23,prevails,O,VBZ
1055,1055,23,there,O,RB
1056,1056,23,",",O,","
1057,1057,23,nor,O,CC
1058,1058,23,doth,O,RB
1059,1059,23,the,O,DT
1060,1060,23,sun,O,NN
1061,1061,23,shine,O,VB
1062,1062,23,nor,O,CC
1063,1063,23,do,O,VB
1064,1064,23,the,O,DT
1065,1065,23,winds,O,NNS
1066,1066,23,blow,O,VB
1067,1067,23,.,O,.
1068,1068,24,And,O,CC
1069,1069,24,",",O,","
1070,1070,24,O,O,UH
1071,1071,24,king,O,NN
1072,1072,24,",",O,","
1073,1073,24,neither,O,CC
1074,1074,24,doth,O,NN
1075,1075,24,senility,O,NN
1076,1076,24,nor,O,CC
1077,1077,24,hunger,O,NN
1078,1078,24,",",O,","
1079,1079,24,nor,O,CC
1080,1080,24,thirst,O,NN
1081,1081,24,",",O,","
1082,1082,24,nor,O,CC
1083,1083,24,death,O,NN
1084,1084,24,",",O,","
1085,1085,24,nor,O,CC
1086,1086,24,fear,O,NN
1087,1087,24,afflict,O,VBP
1088,1088,24,any,O,DT
1089,1089,24,one,O,NN
1090,1090,24,at,O,IN
1091,1091,24,that,O,DT
1092,1092,24,place,O,NN
1093,1093,24,.,O,.
1094,1094,25,And,O,CC
1095,1095,25,",",O,","
1096,1096,25,O,O,UH
1097,1097,25,foremost,O,JJ
1098,1098,25,of,O,IN
1099,1099,25,conquerors,O,NNS
1100,1100,25,",",O,","
1101,1101,25,on,O,IN
1102,1102,25,all,O,DT
1103,1103,25,sides,O,NNS
1104,1104,25,of,O,IN
1105,1105,25,that,O,DT
1106,1106,25,mountain,O,NN
1107,1107,25,",",O,","
1108,1108,25,there,O,EX
1109,1109,25,exist,O,VBP
1110,1110,25,mines,O,NNS
1111,1111,25,of,O,IN
1112,1112,25,gold,O,NN
1113,1113,25,",",O,","
1114,1114,25,resplendent,O,JJ
1115,1115,25,as,O,IN
1116,1116,25,the,O,DT
1117,1117,25,rays,O,NNS
1118,1118,25,of,O,IN
1119,1119,25,the,O,DT
1120,1120,25,sun,O,NN
1121,1121,25,.,O,.
1122,1122,26,And,O,CC
1123,1123,26,O,O,UH
1124,1124,26,king,O,NN
1125,1125,26,",",O,","
1126,1126,26,the,O,DT
1127,1127,26,attendants,O,NNS
1128,1128,26,of,O,IN
1129,1129,26,Kuvera,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1130,1130,26,",",O,","
1131,1131,26,desirous,O,JJ
1132,1132,26,of,O,IN
1133,1133,26,doing,O,VBG
1134,1134,26,good,O,NN
1135,1135,26,to,O,IN
1136,1136,26,him,O,PRP
1137,1137,26,",",O,","
1138,1138,26,protect,O,VBP
1139,1139,26,these,O,DT
1140,1140,26,mines,O,NNS
1141,1141,26,of,O,IN
1142,1142,26,gold,O,NN
1143,1143,26,from,O,IN
1144,1144,26,intruders,O,NNS
1145,1145,26,",",O,","
1146,1146,26,with,O,IN
1147,1147,26,uplifted,O,JJ
1148,1148,26,arms,O,NNS
1149,1149,26,.,O,.
1150,1150,27,Hie,O,VB
1151,1151,27,thee,O,PRP
1152,1152,27,thither,O,RB
1153,1153,27,",",O,","
1154,1154,27,and,O,CC
1155,1155,27,appease,O,VB
1156,1156,27,that,O,DT
1157,1157,27,adorable,O,JJ
1158,1158,27,god,O,NN
1159,1159,27,who,O,WP
1160,1160,27,is,O,VBZ
1161,1161,27,known,O,VBN
1162,1162,27,by,O,IN
1163,1163,27,the,O,DT
1164,1164,27,names,O,NNS
1165,1165,27,of,O,IN
1166,1166,27,Sarva,B-PER,NNP
1167,1167,27,",",O,","
1168,1168,27,Bedha,B-PER,NNP
1169,1169,27,",",O,","
1170,1170,27,Rudra,B-PER,NNP
1171,1171,27,",",O,","
1172,1172,27,Sitikantha,B-PER,NNP
1173,1173,27,",",O,","
1174,1174,27,Surapa,B-PER,NNP
1175,1175,27,",",O,","
1176,1176,27,Suvarcha,O,NNP
1177,1177,27,",",O,","
1178,1178,27,Kapardi,B-PER,NNP
1179,1179,27,",",O,","
1180,1180,27,Karala,B-PER,NNP
1181,1181,27,",",O,","
1182,1182,27,Haryyaksha,B-PER,NNP
1183,1183,27,",",O,","
1184,1184,27,Varada,B-PER,NNP
1185,1185,27,",",O,","
1186,1186,27,Tryaksha,B-PER,NNP
1187,1187,27,",",O,","
1188,1188,27,Pushnodantabhid,O,NNP
1189,1189,27,",",O,","
1190,1190,27,Vamana,B-PER,NNP
1191,1191,27,",",O,","
1192,1192,27,Siva,B-PER,NNP
1193,1193,27,",",O,","
1194,1194,27,Yamya,B-PER,NNP
1195,1195,27,",",O,","
1196,1196,27,Avyaktarupa,O,NNP
1197,1197,27,",",O,","
1198,1198,27,Sadvritta,B-PER,NNP
1199,1199,27,",",O,","
1200,1200,27,Sankara,B-PER,NNP
1201,1201,27,",",O,","
1202,1202,27,Kshemya,B-PER,NNP
1203,1203,27,",",O,","
1204,1204,27,Harikesa,B-PER,NNP
1205,1205,27,",",O,","
1206,1206,27,Sthanu,B-PER,NNP
1207,1207,27,",",O,","
1208,1208,27,Purusha,B-PER,NNP
1209,1209,27,",",O,","
1210,1210,27,Harinetra,B-PER,NNP
1211,1211,27,",",O,","
1212,1212,27,Munda,B-PER,NNP
1213,1213,27,",",O,","
1214,1214,27,Krishna,B-PER,NNP
1215,1215,27,",",O,","
1216,1216,27,Uttarana,B-PER,NNP
1217,1217,27,",",O,","
1218,1218,27,Bhaskara,O,NNP
1219,1219,27,",",O,","
1220,1220,27,Sutirtha,B-PER,NNP
1221,1221,27,",",O,","
1222,1222,27,Devadeva,B-PER,NNP
1223,1223,27,",",O,","
1224,1224,27,Ranha,B-PER,NNP
1225,1225,27,",",O,","
1226,1226,27,Ushnishi,O,NNP
1227,1227,27,",",O,","
1228,1228,27,Suvaktra,B-PER,NNP
1229,1229,27,",",O,","
1230,1230,27,Sahasraksha,B-PER,NNP
1231,1231,27,",",O,","
1232,1232,27,Midhvan,B-PER,NNP
1233,1233,27,",",O,","
1234,1234,27,Girisa,O,NNP
1235,1235,27,",",O,","
1236,1236,27,Prasanta,B-PER,NNP
1237,1237,27,",",O,","
1238,1238,27,Yata,B-PER,NNP
1239,1239,27,",",O,","
1240,1240,27,Chiravasa,B-PER,NNP
1241,1241,27,",",O,","
1242,1242,27,Vilwadanda,B-PER,NNP
1243,1243,27,",",O,","
1244,1244,27,Siddha,B-PER,NNP
1245,1245,27,",",O,","
1246,1246,27,Sarvadandadhara,B-PER,NNP
1247,1247,27,",",O,","
1248,1248,27,Mriga,B-PER,NNP
1249,1249,27,",",O,","
1250,1250,27,Vyadha,B-PER,NNP
1251,1251,27,",",O,","
1252,1252,27,Mahan,B-PER,NNP
1253,1253,27,",",O,","
1254,1254,27,Dhanesa,B-PER,NNP
1255,1255,27,",",O,","
1256,1256,27,Bhava,B-PER,NNP
1257,1257,27,",",O,","
1258,1258,27,Vara,B-PER,NNP
1259,1259,27,",",O,","
1260,1260,27,Somavaktra,B-PER,NNP
1261,1261,27,",",O,","
1262,1262,27,Siddhamantra,B-PER,NNP
1263,1263,27,",",O,","
1264,1264,27,Chakshu,B-PER,NNP
1265,1265,27,",",O,","
1266,1266,27,Hiranyavahu,O,NNP
1267,1267,27,",",O,","
1268,1268,27,Ugra,B-PER,NNP
1269,1269,27,",",O,","
1270,1270,27,Dikpati,B-PER,NNP
1271,1271,27,",",O,","
1272,1272,27,Lelihana,B-PER,NNP
1273,1273,27,",",O,","
1274,1274,27,Goshtha,B-PER,NNP
1275,1275,27,",",O,","
1276,1276,27,Shiddhamantra,B-PER,NNP
1277,1277,27,",",O,","
1278,1278,27,Vrishnu,B-PER,NNP
1279,1279,27,",",O,","
1280,1280,27,Pasupati,B-PER,NNP
1281,1281,27,",",O,","
1282,1282,27,Bhutapati,B-PER,NNP
1283,1283,27,",",O,","
1284,1284,27,Vrisha,B-PER,NNP
1285,1285,27,",",O,","
1286,1286,27,Matribhakta,B-PER,NNP
1287,1287,27,",",O,","
1288,1288,27,Senani,B-PER,NNP
1289,1289,27,",",O,","
1290,1290,27,Madhyama,B-PER,NNP
1291,1291,27,",",O,","
1292,1292,27,Sruvahasta,B-PER,NNP
1293,1293,27,",",O,","
1294,1294,27,Yati,B-PER,NNP
1295,1295,27,",",O,","
1296,1296,27,Dhanwi,O,NNP
1297,1297,27,",",O,","
1298,1298,27,Bhargava,B-PER,NNP
1299,1299,27,",",O,","
1300,1300,27,Aja,B-PER,NNP
1301,1301,27,",",O,","
1302,1302,27,Krishnanetra,B-PER,NNP
1303,1303,27,",",O,","
1304,1304,27,Virupaksha,B-PER,NNP
1305,1305,27,",",O,","
1306,1306,27,Tikshnadanshtra,B-PER,NNP
1307,1307,27,",",O,","
1308,1308,27,Tikshna,B-PER,NNP
1309,1309,27,",",O,","
1310,1310,27,Vaiswanaramukha,B-PER,NNP
1311,1311,27,",",O,","
1312,1312,27,Mahadyuti,B-PER,NNP
1313,1313,27,",",O,","
1314,1314,27,Ananga,B-PER,NNP
1315,1315,27,",",O,","
1316,1316,27,Sarva,B-PER,NNP
1317,1317,27,",",O,","
1318,1318,27,Dikpati,B-PER,NNP
1319,1319,27,",",O,","
1320,1320,27,Bilohita,B-PER,NNP
1321,1321,27,",",O,","
1322,1322,27,Dipta,O,NNP
1323,1323,27,",",O,","
1324,1324,27,Diptaksha,B-PER,NNP
1325,1325,27,",",O,","
1326,1326,27,Mahauja,B-PER,NNP
1327,1327,27,",",O,","
1328,1328,27,Vasuretas,O,NNP
1329,1329,27,",",O,","
1330,1330,27,Suvapu,O,NNP
1331,1331,27,",",O,","
1332,1332,27,Prithu,B-PER,NNP
1333,1333,27,",",O,","
1334,1334,27,Kritivasa,B-PER,NNP
1335,1335,27,",",O,","
1336,1336,27,Kapalmali,B-PER,NNP
1337,1337,27,",",O,","
1338,1338,27,Suvarnamukuta,B-PER,NNP
1339,1339,27,",",O,","
1340,1340,27,Mahadeva,B-PER,NNP
1341,1341,27,",",O,","
1342,1342,27,Krishna,B-PER,NNP
1343,1343,27,",",O,","
1344,1344,27,Tryamvaka,B-PER,NNP
1345,1345,27,",",O,","
1346,1346,27,Anagha,O,NNP
1347,1347,27,",",O,","
1348,1348,27,Krodhana,B-PER,NNP
1349,1349,27,",",O,","
1350,1350,27,Nrisansa,B-PER,NNP
1351,1351,27,",",O,","
1352,1352,27,Mridu,O,NNP
1353,1353,27,",",O,","
1354,1354,27,Vahusali,O,NNP
1355,1355,27,",",O,","
1356,1356,27,Dandi,B-PER,NNP
1357,1357,27,",",O,","
1358,1358,27,Taptatapa,B-PER,NNP
1359,1359,27,",",O,","
1360,1360,27,Akrurakarma,B-PER,NNP
1361,1361,27,",",O,","
1362,1362,27,Sahasrasira,B-PER,NNP
1363,1363,27,",",O,","
1364,1364,27,Sahasra-charana,O,NNP
1365,1365,27,",",O,","
1366,1366,27,Swadha-swarupa,O,NNP
1367,1367,27,",",O,","
1368,1368,27,Vahurupa,O,NNP
1369,1369,27,",",O,","
1370,1370,27,Danshtri,B-PER,NNP
1371,1371,27,",",O,","
1372,1372,27,Pinaki,B-PER,NNP
1373,1373,27,",",O,","
1374,1374,27,Mahadeva,B-PER,NNP
1375,1375,27,",",O,","
1376,1376,27,Mahayogi,B-PER,NNP
1377,1377,27,",",O,","
1378,1378,27,Avyaya,B-PER,NNP
1379,1379,27,",",O,","
1380,1380,27,Trisulahasta,B-PER,NNP
1381,1381,27,",",O,","
1382,1382,27,Varada,B-PER,NNP
1383,1383,27,",",O,","
1384,1384,27,Tryamvaka,B-PER,NNP
1385,1385,27,",",O,","
1386,1386,27,Bhuvaneswara,B-PER,NNP
1387,1387,27,",",O,","
1388,1388,27,Tripuraghna,B-PER,NNP
1389,1389,27,",",O,","
1390,1390,27,Trinayana,B-PER,NNP
1391,1391,27,",",O,","
1392,1392,27,Trilokesa,B-PER,NNP
1393,1393,27,",",O,","
1394,1394,27,Mahanja,B-PER,NNP
1395,1395,27,",",O,","
1396,1396,27,Sarvabhuta-prabhava,O,NNP
1397,1397,27,",",O,","
1398,1398,27,Sarvabhuta-dharana,O,NNP
1399,1399,27,",",O,","
1400,1400,27,Dharanidhara,B-PER,NNP
1401,1401,27,",",O,","
1402,1402,27,Isana,O,NNP
1403,1403,27,",",O,","
1404,1404,27,Sankara,B-PER,NNP
1405,1405,27,",",O,","
1406,1406,27,Sarva,B-PER,NNP
1407,1407,27,",",O,","
1408,1408,27,Siva,B-PER,NNP
1409,1409,27,",",O,","
1410,1410,27,Visveswara,B-PER,NNP
1411,1411,27,",",O,","
1412,1412,27,Bhava,B-PER,NNP
1413,1413,27,",",O,","
1414,1414,27,Umapati,B-PER,NNP
1415,1415,27,",",O,","
1416,1416,27,Pasupati,B-PER,NNP
1417,1417,27,",",O,","
1418,1418,27,Viswarupa,O,NNP
1419,1419,27,",",O,","
1420,1420,27,Maheswara,B-PER,NNP
1421,1421,27,",",O,","
1422,1422,27,Virupaksha,B-PER,NNP
1423,1423,27,",",O,","
1424,1424,27,Dasabhuja,B-PER,NNP
1425,1425,27,",",O,","
1426,1426,27,Vrishavadhwaja,B-PER,NNP
1427,1427,27,",",O,","
1428,1428,27,Ugra,B-PER,NNP
1429,1429,27,",",O,","
1430,1430,27,Sthanu,B-PER,NNP
1431,1431,27,",",O,","
1432,1432,27,Siva,B-PER,NNP
1433,1433,27,",",O,","
1434,1434,27,Rudra,B-PER,NNP
1435,1435,27,",",O,","
1436,1436,27,Sarva,B-PER,NNP
1437,1437,27,",",O,","
1438,1438,27,Girisa,O,NNP
1439,1439,27,",",O,","
1440,1440,27,Iswara,B-PER,NNP
1441,1441,27,",",O,","
1442,1442,27,Sitakantha,B-PER,NNP
1443,1443,27,",",O,","
1444,1444,27,Aja,B-PER,NNP
1445,1445,27,",",O,","
1446,1446,27,Sukra,B-PER,NNP
1447,1447,27,",",O,","
1448,1448,27,Prithu,B-PER,NNP
1449,1449,27,",",O,","
1450,1450,27,Prithuhara,B-PER,NNP
1451,1451,27,",",O,","
1452,1452,27,Vara,B-PER,NNP
1453,1453,27,",",O,","
1454,1454,27,Viswarupa,O,NNP
1455,1455,27,",",O,","
1456,1456,27,Virupaksha,B-PER,NNP
1457,1457,27,",",O,","
1458,1458,27,Vahurupa,O,NNP
1459,1459,27,",",O,","
1460,1460,27,Umapati,B-PER,NNP
1461,1461,27,",",O,","
1462,1462,27,Anangangahara,B-PER,NNP
1463,1463,27,",",O,","
1464,1464,27,Hara,B-PER,NNP
1465,1465,27,",",O,","
1466,1466,27,Saranya,B-PER,NNP
1467,1467,27,",",O,","
1468,1468,27,Mahadeva,B-PER,NNP
1469,1469,27,",",O,","
1470,1470,27,Chaturmukha,B-PER,NNP
1471,1471,27,.,O,.
1472,1472,28,There,O,RB
1473,1473,28,bowing,O,VBG
1474,1474,28,unto,O,IN
1475,1475,28,that,O,DT
1476,1476,28,deity,O,NN
1477,1477,28,",",O,","
1478,1478,28,must,O,MD
1479,1479,28,thou,O,PRP
1480,1480,28,crave,O,VB
1481,1481,28,his,O,PRP$
1482,1482,28,protection,O,NN
1483,1483,28,.,O,.
1484,1484,29,And,O,CC
1485,1485,29,thus,O,RB
1486,1486,29,",",O,","
1487,1487,29,O,O,UH
1488,1488,29,prince,O,NN
1489,1489,29,",",O,","
1490,1490,29,making,O,VBG
1491,1491,29,thy,O,PRP$
1492,1492,29,submission,O,NN
1493,1493,29,to,O,IN
1494,1494,29,that,O,DT
1495,1495,29,high-souled,O,JJ
1496,1496,29,Mahadeva,B-PER,NNP
1497,1497,29,of,O,IN
1498,1498,29,great,O,JJ
1499,1499,29,energy,O,NN
1500,1500,29,",",O,","
1501,1501,29,shalt,O,VB
1502,1502,29,thou,O,PRP
1503,1503,29,acquire,O,VB
1504,1504,29,that,O,DT
1505,1505,29,gold,O,NN
1506,1506,29,.,O,.
1507,1507,30,And,O,CC
1508,1508,30,the,O,DT
1509,1509,30,men,O,NNS
1510,1510,30,who,O,WP
1511,1511,30,go,O,VBP
1512,1512,30,there,O,RB
1513,1513,30,thus,O,RB
1514,1514,30,",",O,","
1515,1515,30,succeed,O,VBP
1516,1516,30,in,O,IN
1517,1517,30,obtaining,O,VBG
1518,1518,30,the,O,DT
1519,1519,30,gold,O,NN
1520,1520,30,.,O,.
1521,1521,30,',O,''
1522,1522,31,Thus,O,RB
1523,1523,31,instructed,O,VBN
1524,1524,31,",",O,","
1525,1525,31,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
1526,1526,31,",",O,","
1527,1527,31,the,O,DT
1528,1528,31,son,O,NN
1529,1529,31,of,O,IN
1530,1530,31,Karandhama,O,NNP
1531,1531,31,",",O,","
1532,1532,31,did,O,VBD
1533,1533,31,as,O,IN
1534,1534,31,he,O,PRP
1535,1535,31,was,O,VBD
1536,1536,31,advised,O,VBN
1537,1537,31,",",O,","
1538,1538,31,and,O,CC
1539,1539,31,made,O,VBD
1540,1540,31,superhuman,O,JJ
1541,1541,31,arrangements,O,NNS
1542,1542,31,for,O,IN
1543,1543,31,the,O,DT
1544,1544,31,performance,O,NN
1545,1545,31,of,O,IN
1546,1546,31,his,O,PRP$
1547,1547,31,sacrifice,O,NN
1548,1548,31,.,O,.
1549,1549,32,And,O,CC
1550,1550,32,artisans,O,NNS
1551,1551,32,manufactured,O,VBN
1552,1552,32,vessels,O,NNS
1553,1553,32,of,O,IN
1554,1554,32,gold,O,NN
1555,1555,32,for,O,IN
1556,1556,32,that,O,DT
1557,1557,32,sacrifice,O,NN
1558,1558,32,.,O,.
1559,1559,33,And,O,CC
1560,1560,33,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1561,1561,33,too,O,RB
1562,1562,33,",",O,","
1563,1563,33,hearing,O,VBG
1564,1564,33,of,O,IN
1565,1565,33,the,O,DT
1566,1566,33,prosperity,O,NN
1567,1567,33,of,O,IN
1568,1568,33,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
1569,1569,33,",",O,","
1570,1570,33,eclipsing,O,VBG
1571,1571,33,that,O,DT
1572,1572,33,of,O,IN
1573,1573,33,the,O,DT
1574,1574,33,gods,O,NNS
1575,1575,33,",",O,","
1576,1576,33,became,O,VBD
1577,1577,33,greatly,O,RB
1578,1578,33,grieved,O,VBN
1579,1579,33,at,O,IN
1580,1580,33,heart,O,NN
1581,1581,33,",",O,","
1582,1582,33,and,O,CC
1583,1583,33,distressed,O,JJ
1584,1584,33,at,O,IN
1585,1585,33,the,O,DT
1586,1586,33,thought,O,NN
1587,1587,33,that,O,IN
1588,1588,33,his,O,PRP$
1589,1589,33,rival,O,NN
1590,1590,33,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
1591,1591,33,should,O,MD
1592,1592,33,become,O,VB
1593,1593,33,prosperous,O,JJ
1594,1594,33,",",O,","
1595,1595,33,became,O,VBD
1596,1596,33,sick,O,JJ
1597,1597,33,at,O,IN
1598,1598,33,heart,O,NN
1599,1599,33,",",O,","
1600,1600,33,and,O,CC
1601,1601,33,the,O,DT
1602,1602,33,glow,O,NN
1603,1603,33,of,O,IN
1604,1604,33,his,O,PRP$
1605,1605,33,complexion,O,NN
1606,1606,33,left,O,VBD
1607,1607,33,him,O,PRP
1608,1608,33,",",O,","
1609,1609,33,and,O,CC
1610,1610,33,his,O,PRP$
1611,1611,33,frame,O,NN
1612,1612,33,became,O,VBD
1613,1613,33,emaciated,O,JJ
1614,1614,33,.,O,.
1615,1615,34,And,O,CC
1616,1616,34,when,O,WRB
1617,1617,34,the,O,DT
1618,1618,34,lord,O,NN
1619,1619,34,of,O,IN
1620,1620,34,the,O,DT
1621,1621,34,gods,O,NNS
1622,1622,34,came,O,VBD
1623,1623,34,to,O,TO
1624,1624,34,know,O,VB
1625,1625,34,that,O,IN
1626,1626,34,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1627,1627,34,was,O,VBD
1628,1628,34,much,O,RB
1629,1629,34,aggrieved,O,JJ
1630,1630,34,",",O,","
1631,1631,34,he,O,PRP
1632,1632,34,went,O,VBD
1633,1633,34,to,O,IN
1634,1634,34,him,O,PRP
1635,1635,34,attended,O,VBN
1636,1636,34,by,O,IN
1637,1637,34,the,O,DT
1638,1638,34,Immortals,O,NNPS
1639,1639,34,and,O,CC
1640,1640,34,addressed,O,VBD
1641,1641,34,him,O,PRP
1642,1642,34,thus,O,RB
1643,1643,34,.,O,.
1644,1644,34,'',O,''
1645,1645,34,',O,''
1646,1646,34,'',O,''
1647,1647,35,SECTION,O,NN
1648,1648,35,IX,O,NNP
1649,1649,35,'',O,''
1650,1650,35,',O,''
1651,1651,35,'',O,''
1652,1652,35,Indra,B-PER,NNP
1653,1653,35,said,O,VBD
1654,1654,35,",",O,","
1655,1655,35,',O,''
1656,1656,35,Dost,O,VB
1657,1657,35,thou,O,PRP
1658,1658,35,",",O,","
1659,1659,35,O,O,UH
1660,1660,35,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1661,1661,35,",",O,","
1662,1662,35,sleep,O,VB
1663,1663,35,in,O,IN
1664,1664,35,peace,O,NN
1665,1665,35,",",O,","
1666,1666,35,and,O,CC
1667,1667,35,are,O,VBP
1668,1668,35,thy,O,PRP$
1669,1669,35,servants,O,NNS
1670,1670,35,agreeable,O,JJ
1671,1671,35,to,O,IN
1672,1672,35,thee,O,PRP
1673,1673,35,",",O,","
1674,1674,35,dost,O,VB
1675,1675,35,thou,O,PRP
1676,1676,35,seek,O,VB
1677,1677,35,the,O,DT
1678,1678,35,welfare,O,NN
1679,1679,35,of,O,IN
1680,1680,35,the,O,DT
1681,1681,35,gods,O,NNS
1682,1682,35,",",O,","
1683,1683,35,and,O,CC
1684,1684,35,do,O,VB
1685,1685,35,the,O,DT
1686,1686,35,gods,O,NNS
1687,1687,35,",",O,","
1688,1688,35,O,O,UH
1689,1689,35,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1690,1690,35,",",O,","
1691,1691,35,protect,O,VB
1692,1692,35,thee,O,PRP
1693,1693,35,?,O,.
1694,1694,35,',O,''
1695,1695,36,``,O,``
1696,1696,36,',O,''
1697,1697,36,'',O,''
1698,1698,36,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1699,1699,36,said,O,VBD
1700,1700,36,",",O,","
1701,1701,36,',O,''
1702,1702,36,I,O,PRP
1703,1703,36,do,O,VBP
1704,1704,36,sleep,O,VB
1705,1705,36,in,O,IN
1706,1706,36,peace,O,NN
1707,1707,36,in,O,IN
1708,1708,36,my,O,PRP$
1709,1709,36,bed,O,NN
1710,1710,36,",",O,","
1711,1711,36,O,O,UH
1712,1712,36,Lord,O,NNP
1713,1713,36,of,O,IN
1714,1714,36,the,O,DT
1715,1715,36,gods,O,NNS
1716,1716,36,",",O,","
1717,1717,36,and,O,CC
1718,1718,36,my,O,PRP$
1719,1719,36,servants,O,NNS
1720,1720,36,are,O,VBP
1721,1721,36,to,O,IN
1722,1722,36,my,O,PRP$
1723,1723,36,liking,O,NN
1724,1724,36,and,O,CC
1725,1725,36,I,O,PRP
1726,1726,36,always,O,RB
1727,1727,36,seek,O,VBP
1728,1728,36,the,O,DT
1729,1729,36,welfare,O,NN
1730,1730,36,of,O,IN
1731,1731,36,the,O,DT
1732,1732,36,gods,O,NNS
1733,1733,36,",",O,","
1734,1734,36,and,O,CC
1735,1735,36,they,O,PRP
1736,1736,36,cherish,O,VBP
1737,1737,36,me,O,PRP
1738,1738,36,well,O,RB
1739,1739,36,.,O,.
1740,1740,36,',O,''
1741,1741,37,``,O,``
1742,1742,37,',O,''
1743,1743,37,'',O,''
1744,1744,37,Indra,B-PER,NNP
1745,1745,37,said,O,VBD
1746,1746,37,",",O,","
1747,1747,37,',O,''
1748,1748,37,Whence,O,RB
1749,1749,37,then,O,RB
1750,1750,37,is,O,VBZ
1751,1751,37,this,O,DT
1752,1752,37,pain,O,NN
1753,1753,37,",",O,","
1754,1754,37,mental,O,JJ
1755,1755,37,or,O,CC
1756,1756,37,physical,O,JJ
1757,1757,37,",",O,","
1758,1758,37,and,O,CC
1759,1759,37,why,O,WRB
1760,1760,37,art,O,NN
1761,1761,37,thou,O,DT
1762,1762,37,pale,O,JJ
1763,1763,37,and,O,CC
1764,1764,37,altered,O,VBN
1765,1765,37,in,O,IN
1766,1766,37,appearance,O,NN
1767,1767,37,(,O,","
1768,1768,37,complexion,O,NN
1769,1769,37,),O,-RRB-
1770,1770,37,at,O,IN
1771,1771,37,present,O,JJ
1772,1772,37,?,O,.
1773,1773,38,Tell,O,VB
1774,1774,38,me,O,PRP
1775,1775,38,",",O,","
1776,1776,38,O,O,UH
1777,1777,38,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1778,1778,38,",",O,","
1779,1779,38,who,O,WP
1780,1780,38,those,O,DT
1781,1781,38,people,O,NNS
1782,1782,38,are,O,VBP
1783,1783,38,",",O,","
1784,1784,38,who,O,WP
1785,1785,38,have,O,VBP
1786,1786,38,caused,O,VBN
1787,1787,38,thee,O,DT
1788,1788,38,pain,O,NN
1789,1789,38,",",O,","
1790,1790,38,so,O,IN
1791,1791,38,that,O,IN
1792,1792,38,I,O,PRP
1793,1793,38,may,O,MD
1794,1794,38,kill,O,VB
1795,1795,38,them,O,PRP
1796,1796,38,all,O,DT
1797,1797,38,.,O,.
1798,1798,38,',O,''
1799,1799,39,``,O,``
1800,1800,39,',O,''
1801,1801,39,'',O,''
1802,1802,39,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1803,1803,39,said,O,VBD
1804,1804,39,",",O,","
1805,1805,39,',O,''
1806,1806,39,O,O,UH
1807,1807,39,Indra,B-PER,NNP
1808,1808,39,",",O,","
1809,1809,39,I,O,PRP
1810,1810,39,have,O,VBP
1811,1811,39,heard,O,VBN
1812,1812,39,that,O,IN
1813,1813,39,Marutta,O,NNP
1814,1814,39,will,O,MD
1815,1815,39,perform,O,VB
1816,1816,39,a,O,DT
1817,1817,39,great,O,JJ
1818,1818,39,sacrifice,O,NN
1819,1819,39,at,O,IN
1820,1820,39,which,O,WDT
1821,1821,39,exquisite,O,JJ
1822,1822,39,presents,O,NNS
1823,1823,39,will,O,MD
1824,1824,39,be,O,VB
1825,1825,39,given,O,VBN
1826,1826,39,by,O,IN
1827,1827,39,him,O,PRP
1828,1828,39,(,O,:
1829,1829,39,to,O,IN
1830,1830,39,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1831,1831,39,),O,","
1832,1832,39,and,O,CC
1833,1833,39,that,O,IN
1834,1834,39,at,O,IN
1835,1835,39,his,O,PRP$
1836,1836,39,sacrifice,O,NN
1837,1837,39,Samvarta,O,NNP
1838,1838,39,will,O,MD
1839,1839,39,act,O,VB
1840,1840,39,as,O,IN
1841,1841,39,the,O,DT
1842,1842,39,officiating,O,VBG
1843,1843,39,priest,O,NN
1844,1844,39,",",O,","
1845,1845,39,and,O,CC
1846,1846,39,therefore,O,RB
1847,1847,39,do,O,VBP
1848,1848,39,I,O,PRP
1849,1849,39,desire,O,VB
1850,1850,39,that,O,IN
1851,1851,39,he,O,PRP
1852,1852,39,may,O,MD
1853,1853,39,not,O,RB
1854,1854,39,officiate,O,VB
1855,1855,39,as,O,IN
1856,1856,39,priest,O,NN
1857,1857,39,at,O,IN
1858,1858,39,that,O,DT
1859,1859,39,sacrifice,O,NN
1860,1860,39,.,O,.
1861,1861,39,',O,''
1862,1862,40,``,O,``
1863,1863,40,',O,''
1864,1864,40,'',O,''
1865,1865,40,Indra,B-PER,NNP
1866,1866,40,said,O,VBD
1867,1867,40,",",O,","
1868,1868,40,',O,''
1869,1869,40,Thou,O,UH
1870,1870,40,",",O,","
1871,1871,40,O,O,UH
1872,1872,40,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
1873,1873,40,",",O,","
1874,1874,40,hast,O,NN
1875,1875,40,attained,O,VBD
1876,1876,40,all,O,PDT
1877,1877,40,the,O,DT
1878,1878,40,object,O,NN
1879,1879,40,of,O,IN
1880,1880,40,thy,O,DT
1881,1881,40,desire,O,NN
1882,1882,40,when,O,WRB
1883,1883,40,thou,O,PRP
1884,1884,40,hast,O,VBP
1885,1885,40,become,O,VBN
1886,1886,40,the,O,DT
1887,1887,40,excellent,O,JJ
1888,1888,40,priest,O,NN
1889,1889,40,of,O,IN
1890,1890,40,the,O,DT
1891,1891,40,gods,O,NNS
1892,1892,40,",",O,","
1893,1893,40,versed,O,VBN
1894,1894,40,in,O,IN
1895,1895,40,all,O,PDT
1896,1896,40,the,O,DT
1897,1897,40,sacred,O,JJ
1898,1898,40,hymns,O,NNS
1899,1899,40,",",O,","
1900,1900,40,and,O,CC
1901,1901,40,hast,O,VBP
1902,1902,40,overreached,O,VBN
1903,1903,40,the,O,DT
1904,1904,40,influence,O,NN
1905,1905,40,of,O,IN
1906,1906,40,death,O,NN
1907,1907,40,and,O,CC
1908,1908,40,dotage,O,NN
1909,1909,40,",",O,","
1910,1910,40,what,O,WP
1911,1911,40,can,O,MD
1912,1912,40,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
1913,1913,40,do,O,VB
1914,1914,40,to,O,IN
1915,1915,40,thee,O,PRP
1916,1916,40,now,O,RB
1917,1917,40,?,O,.
1918,1918,40,',O,''
1919,1919,41,``,O,``
1920,1920,41,',O,''
1921,1921,41,'',O,''
1922,1922,41,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
1923,1923,41,said,O,VBD
1924,1924,41,",",O,","
1925,1925,41,',O,''
1926,1926,41,Prosperity,O,NN
1927,1927,41,of,O,IN
1928,1928,41,a,O,DT
1929,1929,41,rival,O,NN
1930,1930,41,is,O,VBZ
1931,1931,41,always,O,RB
1932,1932,41,painful,O,JJ
1933,1933,41,to,O,IN
1934,1934,41,one,O,PRP
1935,1935,41,'s,O,POS
1936,1936,41,feelings,O,NNS
1937,1937,41,",",O,","
1938,1938,41,and,O,CC
1939,1939,41,for,O,IN
1940,1940,41,this,O,DT
1941,1941,41,reason,O,NN
1942,1942,41,too,O,RB
1943,1943,41,",",O,","
1944,1944,41,thou,O,PRP
1945,1945,41,dost,O,VBP
1946,1946,41,with,O,IN
1947,1947,41,thy,O,PRP$
1948,1948,41,attendant,O,JJ
1949,1949,41,gods,O,NNS
1950,1950,41,persecute,O,VBP
1951,1951,41,the,O,DT
1952,1952,41,Asuras,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
1953,1953,41,with,O,IN
1954,1954,41,their,O,PRP$
1955,1955,41,kith,O,NN
1956,1956,41,and,O,CC
1957,1957,41,kin,O,NN
1958,1958,41,",",O,","
1959,1959,41,and,O,CC
1960,1960,41,kill,O,VBP
1961,1961,41,the,O,DT
1962,1962,41,most,O,RBS
1963,1963,41,prosperous,O,JJ
1964,1964,41,among,O,IN
1965,1965,41,them,O,PRP
1966,1966,41,;,O,","
1967,1967,41,hence,O,RB
1968,1968,41,",",O,","
1969,1969,41,O,O,UH
1970,1970,41,Lord,O,NNP
1971,1971,41,of,O,IN
1972,1972,41,the,O,DT
1973,1973,41,gods,O,NNS
1974,1974,41,",",O,","
1975,1975,41,am,O,VBP
1976,1976,41,I,O,PRP
1977,1977,41,changed,O,VBN
1978,1978,41,in,O,IN
1979,1979,41,appearance,O,NN
1980,1980,41,at,O,IN
1981,1981,41,the,O,DT
1982,1982,41,thought,O,NN
1983,1983,41,that,O,IN
1984,1984,41,my,O,PRP$
1985,1985,41,rival,O,NN
1986,1986,41,is,O,VBZ
1987,1987,41,prospering,O,VBG
1988,1988,41,",",O,","
1989,1989,41,therefore,O,RB
1990,1990,41,",",O,","
1991,1991,41,O,O,UH
1992,1992,41,Indra,B-PER,NNP
1993,1993,41,",",O,","
1994,1994,41,do,O,VBP
1995,1995,41,thou,O,PRP
1996,1996,41,",",O,","
1997,1997,41,by,O,IN
1998,1998,41,all,O,DT
1999,1999,41,means,O,NNS
2000,2000,41,",",O,","
2001,2001,41,restrain,O,VB
2002,2002,41,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
2003,2003,41,and,O,CC
2004,2004,41,king,O,NN
2005,2005,41,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2006,2006,41,.,O,.
2007,2007,41,',O,''
2008,2008,42,``,O,``
2009,2009,42,',O,''
2010,2010,42,'',O,''
2011,2011,42,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2012,2012,42,turning,O,VBG
2013,2013,42,to,O,IN
2014,2014,42,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2015,2015,42,said,O,VBD
2016,2016,42,",",O,","
2017,2017,42,',O,''
2018,2018,42,Do,O,VB
2019,2019,42,thou,O,PRP
2020,2020,42,",",O,","
2021,2021,42,O,O,UH
2022,2022,42,Jataveda,B-PER,NNP
2023,2023,42,",",O,","
2024,2024,42,following,O,VBG
2025,2025,42,my,O,PRP$
2026,2026,42,direction,O,NN
2027,2027,42,",",O,","
2028,2028,42,go,O,VB
2029,2029,42,to,O,IN
2030,2030,42,king,O,NN
2031,2031,42,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2032,2032,42,to,O,TO
2033,2033,42,present,O,VB
2034,2034,42,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2035,2035,42,to,O,IN
2036,2036,42,him,O,PRP
2037,2037,42,",",O,","
2038,2038,42,and,O,CC
2039,2039,42,say,O,VB
2040,2040,42,unto,O,IN
2041,2041,42,him,O,PRP
2042,2042,42,that,O,IN
2043,2043,42,this,O,DT
2044,2044,42,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2045,2045,42,will,O,MD
2046,2046,42,officiate,O,VB
2047,2047,42,at,O,IN
2048,2048,42,his,O,PRP$
2049,2049,42,sacrifice,O,NN
2050,2050,42,and,O,CC
2051,2051,42,make,O,VB
2052,2052,42,him,O,PRP
2053,2053,42,immortal,O,JJ
2054,2054,42,.,O,.
2055,2055,42,',O,''
2056,2056,43,``,O,``
2057,2057,43,',O,''
2058,2058,43,'',O,''
2059,2059,43,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2060,2060,43,said,O,VBD
2061,2061,43,",",O,","
2062,2062,43,',O,''
2063,2063,43,I,O,PRP
2064,2064,43,shall,O,MD
2065,2065,43,presently,O,RB
2066,2066,43,",",O,","
2067,2067,43,O,O,UH
2068,2068,43,adorable,O,JJ
2069,2069,43,one,O,NN
2070,2070,43,",",O,","
2071,2071,43,repair,O,VB
2072,2072,43,thither,O,NN
2073,2073,43,as,O,IN
2074,2074,43,thy,O,DT
2075,2075,43,messenger,O,NN
2076,2076,43,",",O,","
2077,2077,43,to,O,TO
2078,2078,43,present,O,VB
2079,2079,43,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2080,2080,43,to,O,IN
2081,2081,43,king,O,NN
2082,2082,43,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2083,2083,43,",",O,","
2084,2084,43,and,O,CC
2085,2085,43,to,O,TO
2086,2086,43,make,O,VB
2087,2087,43,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2088,2088,43,'s,O,POS
2089,2089,43,words,O,NNS
2090,2090,43,true,O,JJ
2091,2091,43,",",O,","
2092,2092,43,and,O,CC
2093,2093,43,to,O,TO
2094,2094,43,show,O,VB
2095,2095,43,respect,O,NN
2096,2096,43,to,O,IN
2097,2097,43,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2098,2098,43,",",O,","
2099,2099,43,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2100,2100,43,departed,O,VBD
2101,2101,43,.,O,.
2102,2102,43,',O,''
2103,2103,43,'',O,''
2104,2104,44,``,O,``
2105,2105,44,',O,''
2106,2106,44,Vyasa,B-PER,NNP
2107,2107,44,said,O,VBD
2108,2108,44,",",O,","
2109,2109,44,``,O,``
2110,2110,44,Then,O,RB
2111,2111,44,the,O,DT
2112,2112,44,high-souled,O,JJ
2113,2113,44,fire-god,O,NN
2114,2114,44,went,O,VBD
2115,2115,44,on,O,IN
2116,2116,44,his,O,PRP$
2117,2117,44,errand,O,NN
2118,2118,44,",",O,","
2119,2119,44,devastating,O,VBG
2120,2120,44,all,O,PDT
2121,2121,44,the,O,DT
2122,2122,44,forests,O,NNS
2123,2123,44,and,O,CC
2124,2124,44,trees,O,NNS
2125,2125,44,",",O,","
2126,2126,44,like,O,IN
2127,2127,44,unto,O,IN
2128,2128,44,the,O,DT
2129,2129,44,mighty,O,JJ
2130,2130,44,wind,O,NN
2131,2131,44,",",O,","
2132,2132,44,roaring,O,VBG
2133,2133,44,and,O,CC
2134,2134,44,revolving,O,VBG
2135,2135,44,at,O,IN
2136,2136,44,random,O,JJ
2137,2137,44,at,O,IN
2138,2138,44,the,O,DT
2139,2139,44,end,O,NN
2140,2140,44,of,O,IN
2141,2141,44,the,O,DT
2142,2142,44,winter,O,NN
2143,2143,44,season,O,NN
2144,2144,44,.,O,.
2145,2145,44,'',O,''
2146,2146,45,``,O,``
2147,2147,45,',O,''
2148,2148,45,'',O,''
2149,2149,45,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2150,2150,45,said,O,VBD
2151,2151,45,",",O,","
2152,2152,45,',O,''
2153,2153,45,Behold,O,VB
2154,2154,45,!,O,.
2155,2155,46,I,O,PRP
2156,2156,46,find,O,VBP
2157,2157,46,the,O,DT
2158,2158,46,fire-god,O,NN
2159,2159,46,come,O,VB
2160,2160,46,in,O,IN
2161,2161,46,his,O,PRP$
2162,2162,46,own,O,JJ
2163,2163,46,embodiment,O,NN
2164,2164,46,",",O,","
2165,2165,46,this,O,DT
2166,2166,46,day,O,NN
2167,2167,46,",",O,","
2168,2168,46,therefore,O,RB
2169,2169,46,do,O,VBP
2170,2170,46,thou,O,PRP
2171,2171,46,",",O,","
2172,2172,46,O,O,UH
2173,2173,46,Muni,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
2174,2174,46,",",O,","
2175,2175,46,offer,O,VB
2176,2176,46,him,O,PRP
2177,2177,46,a,O,DT
2178,2178,46,seat,O,NN
2179,2179,46,and,O,CC
2180,2180,46,water,O,NN
2181,2181,46,",",O,","
2182,2182,46,and,O,CC
2183,2183,46,a,O,DT
2184,2184,46,cow,O,NN
2185,2185,46,",",O,","
2186,2186,46,and,O,CC
2187,2187,46,water,O,NN
2188,2188,46,for,O,IN
2189,2189,46,washing,O,VBG
2190,2190,46,the,O,DT
2191,2191,46,feet,O,NNS
2192,2192,46,.,O,.
2193,2193,46,',O,''
2194,2194,47,``,O,``
2195,2195,47,',O,''
2196,2196,47,'',O,''
2197,2197,47,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2198,2198,47,said,O,VBD
2199,2199,47,",",O,","
2200,2200,47,',O,''
2201,2201,47,I,O,PRP
2202,2202,47,accept,O,VBP
2203,2203,47,thy,O,PRP$
2204,2204,47,offerings,O,NNS
2205,2205,47,of,O,IN
2206,2206,47,water,O,NN
2207,2207,47,",",O,","
2208,2208,47,seat,O,NN
2209,2209,47,",",O,","
2210,2210,47,and,O,CC
2211,2211,47,water,O,NN
2212,2212,47,for,O,IN
2213,2213,47,washing,O,VBG
2214,2214,47,the,O,DT
2215,2215,47,feet,O,NNS
2216,2216,47,",",O,","
2217,2217,47,O,O,UH
2218,2218,47,sinless,O,JJ
2219,2219,47,one,O,NN
2220,2220,47,",",O,","
2221,2221,47,do,O,VBP
2222,2222,47,thou,O,RB
2223,2223,47,know,O,VB
2224,2224,47,me,O,PRP
2225,2225,47,as,O,IN
2226,2226,47,the,O,DT
2227,2227,47,messenger,O,NN
2228,2228,47,of,O,IN
2229,2229,47,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2230,2230,47,",",O,","
2231,2231,47,come,O,VB
2232,2232,47,to,O,IN
2233,2233,47,thee,O,PRP
2234,2234,47,",",O,","
2235,2235,47,in,O,IN
2236,2236,47,accordance,O,NN
2237,2237,47,with,O,IN
2238,2238,47,his,O,PRP$
2239,2239,47,directions,O,NNS
2240,2240,47,.,O,.
2241,2241,47,',O,''
2242,2242,48,``,O,``
2243,2243,48,',O,''
2244,2244,48,'',O,''
2245,2245,48,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2246,2246,48,said,O,VBD
2247,2247,48,",",O,","
2248,2248,48,',O,''
2249,2249,48,O,O,UH
2250,2250,48,Fire-god,O,NNP
2251,2251,48,",",O,","
2252,2252,48,is,O,VBZ
2253,2253,48,the,O,DT
2254,2254,48,glorious,O,JJ
2255,2255,48,Lord,O,NNP
2256,2256,48,of,O,IN
2257,2257,48,the,O,DT
2258,2258,48,Celestials,O,NNPS
2259,2259,48,happy,O,JJ
2260,2260,48,",",O,","
2261,2261,48,and,O,CC
2262,2262,48,is,O,VBZ
2263,2263,48,he,O,PRP
2264,2264,48,pleased,O,JJ
2265,2265,48,with,O,IN
2266,2266,48,us,O,PRP
2267,2267,48,",",O,","
2268,2268,48,and,O,CC
2269,2269,48,are,O,VBP
2270,2270,48,the,O,DT
2271,2271,48,other,O,JJ
2272,2272,48,gods,O,NNS
2273,2273,48,loyal,O,JJ
2274,2274,48,to,O,IN
2275,2275,48,him,O,PRP
2276,2276,48,?,O,.
2277,2277,49,Do,O,VB
2278,2278,49,thou,O,PRP
2279,2279,49,enlighten,O,VB
2280,2280,49,me,O,PRP
2281,2281,49,duly,O,RB
2282,2282,49,on,O,IN
2283,2283,49,all,O,PDT
2284,2284,49,these,O,DT
2285,2285,49,points,O,NNS
2286,2286,49,.,O,.
2287,2287,49,',O,''
2288,2288,50,``,O,``
2289,2289,50,',O,''
2290,2290,50,'',O,''
2291,2291,50,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2292,2292,50,said,O,VBD
2293,2293,50,",",O,","
2294,2294,50,',O,''
2295,2295,50,O,O,UH
2296,2296,50,lord,O,NNP
2297,2297,50,of,O,IN
2298,2298,50,the,O,DT
2299,2299,50,earth,B-PLACE,NN
2300,2300,50,",",O,","
2301,2301,50,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
2302,2302,50,is,O,VBZ
2303,2303,50,perfectly,O,RB
2304,2304,50,happy,O,JJ
2305,2305,50,",",O,","
2306,2306,50,he,O,PRP
2307,2307,50,is,O,VBZ
2308,2308,50,pleased,O,JJ
2309,2309,50,with,O,IN
2310,2310,50,thee,O,PRP
2311,2311,50,",",O,","
2312,2312,50,and,O,CC
2313,2313,50,wishes,O,VBZ
2314,2314,50,to,O,TO
2315,2315,50,make,O,VB
2316,2316,50,thee,O,PRP
2317,2317,50,free,O,JJ
2318,2318,50,from,O,IN
2319,2319,50,senility,O,NN
2320,2320,50,",",O,","
2321,2321,50,and,O,CC
2322,2322,50,all,O,PDT
2323,2323,50,the,O,DT
2324,2324,50,other,O,JJ
2325,2325,50,gods,O,NNS
2326,2326,50,are,O,VBP
2327,2327,50,loyal,O,JJ
2328,2328,50,to,O,IN
2329,2329,50,him,O,PRP
2330,2330,50,.,O,.
2331,2331,51,Do,O,VB
2332,2332,51,thou,O,PRP
2333,2333,51,",",O,","
2334,2334,51,O,O,UH
2335,2335,51,king,O,NN
2336,2336,51,",",O,","
2337,2337,51,listen,O,VB
2338,2338,51,to,O,IN
2339,2339,51,the,O,DT
2340,2340,51,message,O,NN
2341,2341,51,of,O,IN
2342,2342,51,the,O,DT
2343,2343,51,Lord,O,NNP
2344,2344,51,of,O,IN
2345,2345,51,the,O,DT
2346,2346,51,Celestials,O,NNPS
2347,2347,51,.,O,.
2348,2348,52,And,O,CC
2349,2349,52,the,O,DT
2350,2350,52,object,O,NN
2351,2351,52,for,O,IN
2352,2352,52,which,O,WDT
2353,2353,52,he,O,PRP
2354,2354,52,has,O,VBZ
2355,2355,52,sent,O,VBN
2356,2356,52,me,O,PRP
2357,2357,52,to,O,IN
2358,2358,52,thee,O,PRP
2359,2359,52,is,O,VBZ
2360,2360,52,to,O,TO
2361,2361,52,present,O,VB
2362,2362,52,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2363,2363,52,to,O,IN
2364,2364,52,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2365,2365,52,.,O,.
2366,2366,53,O,O,UH
2367,2367,53,prince,O,NN
2368,2368,53,",",O,","
2369,2369,53,let,O,VB
2370,2370,53,this,O,DT
2371,2371,53,priest,O,NN
2372,2372,53,(,O,","
2373,2373,53,of,O,IN
2374,2374,53,the,O,DT
2375,2375,53,Celestials,O,NNPS
2376,2376,53,),O,-RRB-
2377,2377,53,perform,O,VB
2378,2378,53,thy,O,PRP$
2379,2379,53,sacrifice,O,NN
2380,2380,53,",",O,","
2381,2381,53,and,O,CC
2382,2382,53,make,O,VB
2383,2383,53,thee,O,PRP
2384,2384,53,",",O,","
2385,2385,53,who,O,WP
2386,2386,53,art,O,VBP
2387,2387,53,only,O,RB
2388,2388,53,a,O,DT
2389,2389,53,mortal,O,NN
2390,2390,53,",",O,","
2391,2391,53,attain,O,VB
2392,2392,53,immortality,O,NN
2393,2393,53,.,O,.
2394,2394,53,',O,''
2395,2395,54,``,O,``
2396,2396,54,',O,''
2397,2397,54,'',O,''
2398,2398,54,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2399,2399,54,said,O,VBD
2400,2400,54,",",O,","
2401,2401,54,',O,''
2402,2402,54,This,O,DT
2403,2403,54,twice-born,O,JJ
2404,2404,54,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
2405,2405,54,Samvarta,O,NNP
2406,2406,54,will,O,MD
2407,2407,54,perform,O,VB
2408,2408,54,my,O,PRP$
2409,2409,54,sacrifice,O,NN
2410,2410,54,",",O,","
2411,2411,54,and,O,CC
2412,2412,54,I,O,PRP
2413,2413,54,pray,O,VBP
2414,2414,54,to,O,IN
2415,2415,54,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2416,2416,54,",",O,","
2417,2417,54,that,O,IN
2418,2418,54,he,O,PRP
2419,2419,54,having,O,VBG
2420,2420,54,acted,O,VBN
2421,2421,54,as,O,IN
2422,2422,54,priest,O,NN
2423,2423,54,to,O,IN
2424,2424,54,Mahendra,B-PER,NNP
2425,2425,54,(,O,","
2426,2426,54,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2427,2427,54,),O,-RRB-
2428,2428,54,",",O,","
2429,2429,54,it,O,PRP
2430,2430,54,does,O,VBZ
2431,2431,54,not,O,RB
2432,2432,54,look,O,VB
2433,2433,54,well,O,JJ
2434,2434,54,for,O,IN
2435,2435,54,him,O,PRP
2436,2436,54,now,O,RB
2437,2437,54,to,O,TO
2438,2438,54,act,O,VB
2439,2439,54,as,O,IN
2440,2440,54,priest,O,NN
2441,2441,54,to,O,IN
2442,2442,54,mortal,O,JJ
2443,2443,54,men,O,NNS
2444,2444,54,.,O,.
2445,2445,54,',O,''
2446,2446,55,``,O,``
2447,2447,55,',O,''
2448,2448,55,'',O,''
2449,2449,55,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2450,2450,55,said,O,VBD
2451,2451,55,",",O,","
2452,2452,55,',O,''
2453,2453,55,If,O,IN
2454,2454,55,this,O,DT
2455,2455,55,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2456,2456,55,officiate,O,VBP
2457,2457,55,as,O,IN
2458,2458,55,thy,O,DT
2459,2459,55,priest,O,NN
2460,2460,55,",",O,","
2461,2461,55,then,O,RB
2462,2462,55,shalt,O,VB
2463,2463,55,thou,O,PRP
2464,2464,55,by,O,IN
2465,2465,55,the,O,DT
2466,2466,55,blessings,O,NNS
2467,2467,55,of,O,IN
2468,2468,55,Devaraja,B-PER,NNP
2469,2469,55,(,O,:
2470,2470,55,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2471,2471,55,),O,-RRB-
2472,2472,55,attain,O,VBP
2473,2473,55,the,O,DT
2474,2474,55,highest,O,JJS
2475,2475,55,region,O,NN
2476,2476,55,in,O,IN
2477,2477,55,the,O,DT
2478,2478,55,celestial,O,JJ
2479,2479,55,mansion,O,NN
2480,2480,55,and,O,CC
2481,2481,55,attaining,O,VBG
2482,2482,55,fame,O,NN
2483,2483,55,shalt,O,NN
2484,2484,55,thou,O,RB
2485,2485,55,certainly,O,RB
2486,2486,55,conquer,O,VB
2487,2487,55,the,O,DT
2488,2488,55,heavenly,O,JJ
2489,2489,55,region,O,NN
2490,2490,55,.,O,.
2491,2491,56,And,O,CC
2492,2492,56,",",O,","
2493,2493,56,O,O,UH
2494,2494,56,lord,O,NN
2495,2495,56,of,O,IN
2496,2496,56,men,O,NNS
2497,2497,56,",",O,","
2498,2498,56,if,O,IN
2499,2499,56,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2500,2500,56,act,O,VBP
2501,2501,56,as,O,IN
2502,2502,56,thy,O,DT
2503,2503,56,priest,O,NN
2504,2504,56,",",O,","
2505,2505,56,thou,O,PRP
2506,2506,56,shalt,O,MD
2507,2507,56,be,O,VB
2508,2508,56,able,O,JJ
2509,2509,56,to,O,TO
2510,2510,56,conquer,O,VB
2511,2511,56,all,O,PDT
2512,2512,56,the,O,DT
2513,2513,56,regions,O,NNS
2514,2514,56,inhabited,O,VBN
2515,2515,56,by,O,IN
2516,2516,56,men,O,NNS
2517,2517,56,",",O,","
2518,2518,56,and,O,CC
2519,2519,56,the,O,DT
2520,2520,56,heavenly,O,JJ
2521,2521,56,regions,O,NNS
2522,2522,56,",",O,","
2523,2523,56,and,O,CC
2524,2524,56,all,O,PDT
2525,2525,56,the,O,DT
2526,2526,56,highest,O,JJS
2527,2527,56,regions,O,NNS
2528,2528,56,created,O,VBN
2529,2529,56,by,O,IN
2530,2530,56,Prajapati,B-PER,NNP
2531,2531,56,and,O,CC
2532,2532,56,even,O,RB
2533,2533,56,the,O,DT
2534,2534,56,entire,O,JJ
2535,2535,56,kingdom,O,NN
2536,2536,56,of,O,IN
2537,2537,56,the,O,DT
2538,2538,56,gods,O,NNS
2539,2539,56,.,O,.
2540,2540,56,',O,''
2541,2541,57,``,O,``
2542,2542,57,',O,''
2543,2543,57,'',O,''
2544,2544,57,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
2545,2545,57,said,O,VBD
2546,2546,57,",",O,","
2547,2547,57,',O,''
2548,2548,57,Thou,O,PRP
2549,2549,57,must,O,MD
2550,2550,57,never,O,RB
2551,2551,57,come,O,VB
2552,2552,57,again,O,RB
2553,2553,57,thus,O,RB
2554,2554,57,to,O,TO
2555,2555,57,present,O,VB
2556,2556,57,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2557,2557,57,to,O,IN
2558,2558,57,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2559,2559,57,:,O,:
2560,2560,57,for,O,IN
2561,2561,57,know,O,NN
2562,2562,57,",",O,","
2563,2563,57,O,O,UH
2564,2564,57,Pavaka,O,NNP
2565,2565,57,",",O,","
2566,2566,57,(,O,","
2567,2567,57,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2568,2568,57,),O,","
2569,2569,57,if,O,IN
2570,2570,57,thou,O,PRP
2571,2571,57,dost,O,VBP
2572,2572,57,",",O,","
2573,2573,57,I,O,PRP
2574,2574,57,losing,O,VBG
2575,2575,57,my,O,PRP$
2576,2576,57,temper,O,NN
2577,2577,57,",",O,","
2578,2578,57,will,O,MD
2579,2579,57,burn,O,VB
2580,2580,57,thee,O,PRP
2581,2581,57,with,O,IN
2582,2582,57,my,O,PRP$
2583,2583,57,fierce,O,JJ
2584,2584,57,evil,O,JJ
2585,2585,57,eyes,O,NNS
2586,2586,57,.,O,.
2587,2587,57,',O,''
2588,2588,57,'',O,''
2589,2589,58,``,O,``
2590,2590,58,',O,''
2591,2591,58,Vyasa,B-PER,NNP
2592,2592,58,said,O,VBD
2593,2593,58,",",O,","
2594,2594,58,``,O,``
2595,2595,58,Then,O,RB
2596,2596,58,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2597,2597,58,apprehending,O,VBG
2598,2598,58,destruction,O,NN
2599,2599,58,by,O,IN
2600,2600,58,fire,O,NN
2601,2601,58,",",O,","
2602,2602,58,and,O,CC
2603,2603,58,trembling,O,VBG
2604,2604,58,like,O,IN
2605,2605,58,the,O,DT
2606,2606,58,leaves,O,NNS
2607,2607,58,of,O,IN
2608,2608,58,the,O,DT
2609,2609,58,Aswattha,O,NNP
2610,2610,58,tree,O,NN
2611,2611,58,(,O,","
2612,2612,58,Ficus,O,NNP
2613,2613,58,religiosa,O,NNP
2614,2614,58,),O,-RRB-
2615,2615,58,",",O,","
2616,2616,58,returned,O,VBN
2617,2617,58,to,O,IN
2618,2618,58,the,O,DT
2619,2619,58,gods,O,NNS
2620,2620,58,",",O,","
2621,2621,58,and,O,CC
2622,2622,58,the,O,DT
2623,2623,58,high-souled,O,JJ
2624,2624,58,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
2625,2625,58,seeing,O,VBG
2626,2626,58,that,O,DT
2627,2627,58,carrier,O,NN
2628,2628,58,of,O,IN
2629,2629,58,oblations,O,NNS
2630,2630,58,(,O,","
2631,2631,58,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2632,2632,58,),O,-RRB-
2633,2633,58,in,O,IN
2634,2634,58,the,O,DT
2635,2635,58,company,O,NN
2636,2636,58,of,O,IN
2637,2637,58,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2638,2638,58,said,O,VBD
2639,2639,58,as,O,IN
2640,2640,58,follows,O,VBZ
2641,2641,58,:,O,:
2642,2642,58,'',O,''
2643,2643,58,',O,''
2644,2644,58,'',O,''
2645,2645,58,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2646,2646,58,said,O,VBD
2647,2647,58,",",O,","
2648,2648,58,',O,''
2649,2649,58,O,O,UH
2650,2650,58,Jataveda,B-PER,NNP
2651,2651,58,(,O,","
2652,2652,58,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2653,2653,58,),O,-RRB-
2654,2654,58,",",O,","
2655,2655,58,didst,O,VBD
2656,2656,58,thou,O,PRP
2657,2657,58,go,O,VB
2658,2658,58,to,O,TO
2659,2659,58,present,O,VB
2660,2660,58,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2661,2661,58,to,O,IN
2662,2662,58,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2663,2663,58,according,O,VBG
2664,2664,58,to,O,IN
2665,2665,58,my,O,PRP$
2666,2666,58,direction,O,NN
2667,2667,58,?,O,.
2668,2668,59,What,O,WP
2669,2669,59,did,O,VBD
2670,2670,59,that,O,DT
2671,2671,59,sacrificing,O,VBG
2672,2672,59,king,O,NN
2673,2673,59,say,O,VB
2674,2674,59,unto,O,IN
2675,2675,59,thee,O,PRP
2676,2676,59,and,O,CC
2677,2677,59,did,O,VBD
2678,2678,59,he,O,PRP
2679,2679,59,accept,O,VB
2680,2680,59,my,O,PRP$
2681,2681,59,message,O,NN
2682,2682,59,?,O,.
2683,2683,59,',O,''
2684,2684,60,``,O,``
2685,2685,60,',O,''
2686,2686,60,'',O,''
2687,2687,60,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2688,2688,60,said,O,VBD
2689,2689,60,",",O,","
2690,2690,60,',O,''
2691,2691,60,Thy,O,DT
2692,2692,60,message,O,NN
2693,2693,60,was,O,VBD
2694,2694,60,not,O,RB
2695,2695,60,acceptable,O,JJ
2696,2696,60,by,O,IN
2697,2697,60,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2698,2698,60,and,O,CC
2699,2699,60,when,O,WRB
2700,2700,60,urged,O,VBN
2701,2701,60,by,O,IN
2702,2702,60,me,O,PRP
2703,2703,60,",",O,","
2704,2704,60,he,O,PRP
2705,2705,60,clasping,O,VBG
2706,2706,60,the,O,DT
2707,2707,60,hands,O,NNS
2708,2708,60,of,O,IN
2709,2709,60,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2710,2710,60,",",O,","
2711,2711,60,repeatedly,O,RB
2712,2712,60,said,O,VBD
2713,2713,60,",",O,","
2714,2714,60,that,O,IN
2715,2715,60,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
2716,2716,60,would,O,MD
2717,2717,60,act,O,VB
2718,2718,60,as,O,IN
2719,2719,60,his,O,PRP$
2720,2720,60,priest,O,NN
2721,2721,60,.,O,.
2722,2722,61,And,O,CC
2723,2723,61,he,O,PRP
2724,2724,61,also,O,RB
2725,2725,61,observed,O,VBD
2726,2726,61,that,O,IN
2727,2727,61,he,O,PRP
2728,2728,61,did,O,VBD
2729,2729,61,not,O,RB
2730,2730,61,desire,O,VB
2731,2731,61,to,O,TO
2732,2732,61,attain,O,VB
2733,2733,61,the,O,DT
2734,2734,61,worldly,O,JJ
2735,2735,61,and,O,CC
2736,2736,61,the,O,DT
2737,2737,61,heavenly,O,JJ
2738,2738,61,regions,O,NNS
2739,2739,61,and,O,CC
2740,2740,61,all,O,PDT
2741,2741,61,the,O,DT
2742,2742,61,highest,O,JJS
2743,2743,61,regions,O,NNS
2744,2744,61,of,O,IN
2745,2745,61,Prajapati,B-PER,NNP
2746,2746,61,",",O,","
2747,2747,61,and,O,CC
2748,2748,61,that,O,IN
2749,2749,61,if,O,IN
2750,2750,61,he,O,PRP
2751,2751,61,were,O,VBD
2752,2752,61,so,O,RB
2753,2753,61,minded,O,JJ
2754,2754,61,",",O,","
2755,2755,61,he,O,PRP
2756,2756,61,would,O,MD
2757,2757,61,accept,O,VB
2758,2758,61,the,O,DT
2759,2759,61,terms,O,NNS
2760,2760,61,of,O,IN
2761,2761,61,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2762,2762,61,.,O,.
2763,2763,61,',O,''
2764,2764,62,``,O,``
2765,2765,62,',O,''
2766,2766,62,'',O,''
2767,2767,62,Indra,B-PER,NNP
2768,2768,62,said,O,VBD
2769,2769,62,",",O,","
2770,2770,62,',O,''
2771,2771,62,Do,O,VB
2772,2772,62,thou,O,PRP
2773,2773,62,go,O,VB
2774,2774,62,back,O,RB
2775,2775,62,to,O,IN
2776,2776,62,that,O,DT
2777,2777,62,king,O,NN
2778,2778,62,and,O,CC
2779,2779,62,meeting,O,VBG
2780,2780,62,him,O,PRP
2781,2781,62,",",O,","
2782,2782,62,tell,O,VB
2783,2783,62,him,O,PRP
2784,2784,62,these,O,DT
2785,2785,62,words,O,NNS
2786,2786,62,of,O,IN
2787,2787,62,mine,O,NN
2788,2788,62,",",O,","
2789,2789,62,full,O,JJ
2790,2790,62,of,O,IN
2791,2791,62,significance,O,NN
2792,2792,62,",",O,","
2793,2793,62,and,O,CC
2794,2794,62,if,O,IN
2795,2795,62,he,O,PRP
2796,2796,62,obey,O,VBP
2797,2797,62,them,O,PRP
2798,2798,62,not,O,RB
2799,2799,62,",",O,","
2800,2800,62,I,O,PRP
2801,2801,62,shall,O,MD
2802,2802,62,strike,O,VB
2803,2803,62,him,O,PRP
2804,2804,62,with,O,IN
2805,2805,62,my,O,PRP$
2806,2806,62,thunderbolt,O,NN
2807,2807,62,.,O,.
2808,2808,62,',O,''
2809,2809,63,``,O,``
2810,2810,63,',O,''
2811,2811,63,'',O,''
2812,2812,63,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2813,2813,63,said,O,VBD
2814,2814,63,",",O,","
2815,2815,63,',O,''
2816,2816,63,Let,O,VB
2817,2817,63,this,O,DT
2818,2818,63,king,O,NN
2819,2819,63,of,O,IN
2820,2820,63,the,O,DT
2821,2821,63,Gandharvas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
2822,2822,63,repair,O,VB
2823,2823,63,thither,O,NN
2824,2824,63,as,O,IN
2825,2825,63,thy,O,DT
2826,2826,63,messenger,O,NN
2827,2827,63,",",O,","
2828,2828,63,O,O,UH
2829,2829,63,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
2830,2830,63,",",O,","
2831,2831,63,for,O,CC
2832,2832,63,",",O,","
2833,2833,63,I,O,PRP
2834,2834,63,am,O,VBP
2835,2835,63,afraid,O,JJ
2836,2836,63,to,O,TO
2837,2837,63,go,O,VB
2838,2838,63,thither,O,RB
2839,2839,63,myself,O,PRP
2840,2840,63,.,O,.
2841,2841,64,Know,O,VB
2842,2842,64,",",O,","
2843,2843,64,O,O,UH
2844,2844,64,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
2845,2845,64,",",O,","
2846,2846,64,that,O,IN
2847,2847,64,highly,O,RB
2848,2848,64,incensed,O,JJ
2849,2849,64,Samvarta,O,NNP
2850,2850,64,",",O,","
2851,2851,64,used,O,VBN
2852,2852,64,to,O,IN
2853,2853,64,ascetic,O,JJ
2854,2854,64,practices,O,NNS
2855,2855,64,",",O,","
2856,2856,64,told,O,VBD
2857,2857,64,me,O,PRP
2858,2858,64,these,O,DT
2859,2859,64,words,O,NNS
2860,2860,64,in,O,IN
2861,2861,64,a,O,DT
2862,2862,64,rage,O,NN
2863,2863,64,.,O,.
2864,2864,65,',O,''
2865,2865,65,I,O,PRP
2866,2866,65,shall,O,MD
2867,2867,65,burn,O,VB
2868,2868,65,thee,O,PRP
2869,2869,65,with,O,IN
2870,2870,65,my,O,PRP$
2871,2871,65,fierce,O,JJ
2872,2872,65,evil,O,JJ
2873,2873,65,eyes,O,NNS
2874,2874,65,if,O,IN
2875,2875,65,thou,O,PRP
2876,2876,65,on,O,IN
2877,2877,65,any,O,DT
2878,2878,65,account,O,NN
2879,2879,65,come,O,VBP
2880,2880,65,again,O,RB
2881,2881,65,here,O,RB
2882,2882,65,to,O,TO
2883,2883,65,present,O,VB
2884,2884,65,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
2885,2885,65,to,O,IN
2886,2886,65,king,O,NN
2887,2887,65,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
2888,2888,65,.,O,.
2889,2889,65,',O,''
2890,2890,66,``,O,``
2891,2891,66,',O,''
2892,2892,66,'',O,''
2893,2893,66,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
2894,2894,66,said,O,VBD
2895,2895,66,",",O,","
2896,2896,66,',O,''
2897,2897,66,O,O,UH
2898,2898,66,Jataveda,B-PER,NNP
2899,2899,66,",",O,","
2900,2900,66,it,O,PRP
2901,2901,66,is,O,VBZ
2902,2902,66,thou,O,DT
2903,2903,66,who,O,WP
2904,2904,66,dost,O,VBP
2905,2905,66,burn,O,VB
2906,2906,66,all,O,DT
2907,2907,66,other,O,JJ
2908,2908,66,things,O,NNS
2909,2909,66,and,O,CC
2910,2910,66,there,O,EX
2911,2911,66,is,O,VBZ
2912,2912,66,none,O,NN
2913,2913,66,else,O,RB
2914,2914,66,who,O,WP
2915,2915,66,can,O,MD
2916,2916,66,reduce,O,VB
2917,2917,66,thee,O,PRP
2918,2918,66,to,O,IN
2919,2919,66,ashes,O,NNS
2920,2920,66,.,O,.
2921,2921,67,All,O,PDT
2922,2922,67,the,O,DT
2923,2923,67,world,O,NN
2924,2924,67,is,O,VBZ
2925,2925,67,afraid,O,JJ
2926,2926,67,to,O,TO
2927,2927,67,come,O,VB
2928,2928,67,in,O,IN
2929,2929,67,contact,O,NN
2930,2930,67,with,O,IN
2931,2931,67,thee,O,PRP
2932,2932,67,.,O,.
2933,2933,68,O,O,UH
2934,2934,68,carrier,O,NN
2935,2935,68,of,O,IN
2936,2936,68,oblations,O,NNS
2937,2937,68,",",O,","
2938,2938,68,these,O,DT
2939,2939,68,words,O,NNS
2940,2940,68,of,O,IN
2941,2941,68,thine,O,NN
2942,2942,68,are,O,VBP
2943,2943,68,worthy,O,JJ
2944,2944,68,of,O,IN
2945,2945,68,no,O,DT
2946,2946,68,credence,O,NN
2947,2947,68,.,O,.
2948,2948,68,',O,''
2949,2949,69,``,O,``
2950,2950,69,',O,''
2951,2951,69,'',O,''
2952,2952,69,Agni,B-PER,NNP
2953,2953,69,said,O,VBD
2954,2954,69,",",O,","
2955,2955,69,',O,''
2956,2956,69,Thou,O,UH
2957,2957,69,",",O,","
2958,2958,69,O,O,UH
2959,2959,69,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
2960,2960,69,",",O,","
2961,2961,69,hast,O,NN
2962,2962,69,encompassed,O,VBD
2963,2963,69,the,O,DT
2964,2964,69,dominion,O,NN
2965,2965,69,of,O,IN
2966,2966,69,the,O,DT
2967,2967,69,heaven,O,NNP
2968,2968,69,and,O,CC
2969,2969,69,the,O,DT
2970,2970,69,earth,B-PLACE,NN
2971,2971,69,and,O,CC
2972,2972,69,the,O,DT
2973,2973,69,firmament,O,NN
2974,2974,69,by,O,IN
2975,2975,69,the,O,DT
2976,2976,69,might,O,NN
2977,2977,69,of,O,IN
2978,2978,69,thy,O,DT
2979,2979,69,own,O,JJ
2980,2980,69,arms,O,NNS
2981,2981,69,",",O,","
2982,2982,69,but,O,CC
2983,2983,69,even,O,RB
2984,2984,69,thus,O,RB
2985,2985,69,how,O,WRB
2986,2986,69,could,O,MD
2987,2987,69,Vritra,B-PER,NNP
2988,2988,69,(,O,","
2989,2989,69,of,O,IN
2990,2990,69,old,O,JJ
2991,2991,69,),O,","
2992,2992,69,wrest,O,VB
2993,2993,69,from,O,IN
2994,2994,69,thee,O,PRP
2995,2995,69,the,O,DT
2996,2996,69,sovereignty,O,NN
2997,2997,69,of,O,IN
2998,2998,69,the,O,DT
2999,2999,69,celestial,O,JJ
3000,3000,69,regions,O,NNS
3001,3001,69,?,O,.
3002,3002,69,',O,''
3003,3003,70,``,O,``
3004,3004,70,',O,''
3005,3005,70,'',O,''
3006,3006,70,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3007,3007,70,said,O,VBD
3008,3008,70,",",O,","
3009,3009,70,',O,''
3010,3010,70,I,O,PRP
3011,3011,70,can,O,MD
3012,3012,70,reduce,O,VB
3013,3013,70,my,O,PRP$
3014,3014,70,foes,O,NNS
3015,3015,70,to,O,IN
3016,3016,70,submission,O,NN
3017,3017,70,and,O,CC
3018,3018,70,can,O,MD
3019,3019,70,even,O,RB
3020,3020,70,reduce,O,VB
3021,3021,70,the,O,DT
3022,3022,70,size,O,NN
3023,3023,70,of,O,IN
3024,3024,70,a,O,DT
3025,3025,70,mountain,O,NN
3026,3026,70,to,O,IN
3027,3027,70,an,O,DT
3028,3028,70,atom,O,NN
3029,3029,70,",",O,","
3030,3030,70,if,O,IN
3031,3031,70,I,O,PRP
3032,3032,70,will,O,MD
3033,3033,70,it,O,PRP
3034,3034,70,.,O,.
3035,3035,71,But,O,CC
3036,3036,71,",",O,","
3037,3037,71,O,O,UH
3038,3038,71,Vahnni,B-PER,NNP
3039,3039,71,",",O,","
3040,3040,71,as,O,IN
3041,3041,71,I,O,PRP
3042,3042,71,do,O,VBP
3043,3043,71,not,O,RB
3044,3044,71,accept,O,VB
3045,3045,71,the,O,DT
3046,3046,71,libation,O,NN
3047,3047,71,of,O,IN
3048,3048,71,Soma,B-PER,NNP
3049,3049,71,if,O,IN
3050,3050,71,offered,O,VBN
3051,3051,71,by,O,IN
3052,3052,71,a,O,DT
3053,3053,71,foe,O,NN
3054,3054,71,",",O,","
3055,3055,71,and,O,CC
3056,3056,71,as,O,IN
3057,3057,71,I,O,PRP
3058,3058,71,do,O,VBP
3059,3059,71,not,O,RB
3060,3060,71,strike,O,VB
3061,3061,71,the,O,DT
3062,3062,71,weak,O,JJ
3063,3063,71,with,O,IN
3064,3064,71,my,O,PRP$
3065,3065,71,thunderbolt,O,NN
3066,3066,71,",",O,","
3067,3067,71,Vritra,B-PER,NNP
3068,3068,71,seemed,O,VBD
3069,3069,71,to,O,TO
3070,3070,71,triumph,O,VB
3071,3071,71,over,O,IN
3072,3072,71,me,O,PRP
3073,3073,71,for,O,IN
3074,3074,71,a,O,DT
3075,3075,71,time,O,NN
3076,3076,71,.,O,.
3077,3077,72,But,O,CC
3078,3078,72,who,O,WP
3079,3079,72,among,O,IN
3080,3080,72,mortals,O,NNS
3081,3081,72,can,O,MD
3082,3082,72,live,O,VB
3083,3083,72,in,O,IN
3084,3084,72,peace,O,NN
3085,3085,72,by,O,IN
3086,3086,72,creating,O,VBG
3087,3087,72,feud,O,NN
3088,3088,72,with,O,IN
3089,3089,72,me,O,PRP
3090,3090,72,.,O,.
3091,3091,73,I,O,PRP
3092,3092,73,have,O,VBP
3093,3093,73,banished,O,VBN
3094,3094,73,the,O,DT
3095,3095,73,Kalakeyas,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
3096,3096,73,to,O,IN
3097,3097,73,the,O,DT
3098,3098,73,earth,B-PLACE,NN
3099,3099,73,",",O,","
3100,3100,73,and,O,CC
3101,3101,73,removed,O,VBD
3102,3102,73,the,O,DT
3103,3103,73,Danavas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3104,3104,73,from,O,IN
3105,3105,73,heaven,O,NNP
3106,3106,73,",",O,","
3107,3107,73,and,O,CC
3108,3108,73,have,O,VBP
3109,3109,73,terminated,O,VBN
3110,3110,73,the,O,DT
3111,3111,73,existence,O,NN
3112,3112,73,of,O,IN
3113,3113,73,Prahlada,B-PER,NNP
3114,3114,73,in,O,IN
3115,3115,73,heaven,O,NNP
3116,3116,73,.,O,.
3117,3117,74,Can,O,MD
3118,3118,74,there,O,EX
3119,3119,74,be,O,VB
3120,3120,74,any,O,DT
3121,3121,74,man,O,NN
3122,3122,74,who,O,WP
3123,3123,74,can,O,MD
3124,3124,74,live,O,VB
3125,3125,74,in,O,IN
3126,3126,74,peace,O,NN
3127,3127,74,by,O,IN
3128,3128,74,provoking,O,VBG
3129,3129,74,my,O,PRP$
3130,3130,74,enmity,O,NN
3131,3131,74,?,O,.
3132,3132,74,',O,''
3133,3133,75,``,O,``
3134,3134,75,',O,''
3135,3135,75,'',O,''
3136,3136,75,Agni,B-PER,NNP
3137,3137,75,said,O,VBD
3138,3138,75,",",O,","
3139,3139,75,',O,''
3140,3140,75,Dost,O,VB
3141,3141,75,thou,O,PRP
3142,3142,75,",",O,","
3143,3143,75,O,O,NNP
3144,3144,75,Mahendra,B-PER,NNP
3145,3145,75,",",O,","
3146,3146,75,remember,O,VB
3147,3147,75,that,O,IN
3148,3148,75,in,O,IN
3149,3149,75,olden,O,JJ
3150,3150,75,times,O,NNS
3151,3151,75,when,O,WRB
3152,3152,75,the,O,DT
3153,3153,75,sage,O,NN
3154,3154,75,Chyavana,B-PER,NNP
3155,3155,75,officiated,O,VBD
3156,3156,75,at,O,IN
3157,3157,75,the,O,DT
3158,3158,75,sacrifice,O,NN
3159,3159,75,of,O,IN
3160,3160,75,Saryati,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3161,3161,75,with,O,IN
3162,3162,75,the,O,DT
3163,3163,75,twin,O,JJ
3164,3164,75,gods,O,NNS
3165,3165,75,Aswins,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
3166,3166,75,and,O,CC
3167,3167,75,himself,O,PRP
3168,3168,75,appropriated,O,VBD
3169,3169,75,the,O,DT
3170,3170,75,Soma,B-PER,NNP
3171,3171,75,offering,O,NN
3172,3172,75,alone,O,RB
3173,3173,75,",",O,","
3174,3174,75,thou,O,RB
3175,3175,75,wert,O,VBD
3176,3176,75,filled,O,VBN
3177,3177,75,with,O,IN
3178,3178,75,wrath,O,NN
3179,3179,75,",",O,","
3180,3180,75,and,O,CC
3181,3181,75,when,O,WRB
3182,3182,75,bent,O,VBN
3183,3183,75,upon,O,IN
3184,3184,75,preventing,O,VBG
3185,3185,75,Saryati,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3186,3186,75,',O,''
3187,3187,75,s,O,POS
3188,3188,75,sacrifice,O,NN
3189,3189,75,",",O,","
3190,3190,75,thou,O,PRP
3191,3191,75,didst,O,VBP
3192,3192,75,violently,O,RB
3193,3193,75,strike,O,VB
3194,3194,75,Chyavana,B-PER,NNP
3195,3195,75,with,O,IN
3196,3196,75,thy,O,DT
3197,3197,75,thunderbolt,O,NN
3198,3198,75,?,O,.
3199,3199,76,But,O,CC
3200,3200,76,that,O,DT
3201,3201,76,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3202,3202,76,",",O,","
3203,3203,76,O,O,UH
3204,3204,76,Purandara,B-PER,NNP
3205,3205,76,",",O,","
3206,3206,76,giving,O,VBG
3207,3207,76,way,O,NN
3208,3208,76,to,O,IN
3209,3209,76,passion,O,NN
3210,3210,76,",",O,","
3211,3211,76,was,O,VBD
3212,3212,76,able,O,JJ
3213,3213,76,by,O,IN
3214,3214,76,the,O,DT
3215,3215,76,power,O,NN
3216,3216,76,of,O,IN
3217,3217,76,his,O,PRP$
3218,3218,76,devotions,O,NNS
3219,3219,76,to,O,TO
3220,3220,76,seize,O,VB
3221,3221,76,and,O,CC
3222,3222,76,hold,O,VB
3223,3223,76,fast,O,RB
3224,3224,76,by,O,IN
3225,3225,76,hand,O,NN
3226,3226,76,with,O,IN
3227,3227,76,thy,O,PRP$
3228,3228,76,thunder-bolt,O,NN
3229,3229,76,in,O,IN
3230,3230,76,it,O,PRP
3231,3231,76,.,O,.
3232,3232,77,And,O,CC
3233,3233,77,in,O,IN
3234,3234,77,a,O,DT
3235,3235,77,rage,O,NN
3236,3236,77,",",O,","
3237,3237,77,he,O,PRP
3238,3238,77,again,O,RB
3239,3239,77,created,O,VBD
3240,3240,77,a,O,DT
3241,3241,77,terrible,O,JJ
3242,3242,77,looking,O,VBG
3243,3243,77,enemy,O,NN
3244,3244,77,of,O,IN
3245,3245,77,thine,O,NN
3246,3246,77,",",O,","
3247,3247,77,the,O,DT
3248,3248,77,Asura,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3249,3249,77,named,O,VBN
3250,3250,77,Mada,B-PER,NNP
3251,3251,77,assuming,O,VBG
3252,3252,77,all,O,DT
3253,3253,77,shapes,O,NNS
3254,3254,77,",",O,","
3255,3255,77,on,O,IN
3256,3256,77,beholding,O,VBG
3257,3257,77,whom,O,WP
3258,3258,77,thou,O,PRP
3259,3259,77,didst,O,VBD
3260,3260,77,shut,O,VBD
3261,3261,77,thine,O,NN
3262,3262,77,eyes,O,NNS
3263,3263,77,with,O,IN
3264,3264,77,fear,O,NN
3265,3265,77,",",O,","
3266,3266,77,whose,O,WP$
3267,3267,77,one,O,CD
3268,3268,77,huge,O,JJ
3269,3269,77,jaw,O,NN
3270,3270,77,was,O,VBD
3271,3271,77,placed,O,VBN
3272,3272,77,on,O,IN
3273,3273,77,earth,B-PLACE,NN
3274,3274,77,",",O,","
3275,3275,77,and,O,CC
3276,3276,77,the,O,DT
3277,3277,77,other,O,JJ
3278,3278,77,extended,O,VBD
3279,3279,77,to,O,IN
3280,3280,77,the,O,DT
3281,3281,77,celestial,O,JJ
3282,3282,77,regions,O,NNS
3283,3283,77,",",O,","
3284,3284,77,and,O,CC
3285,3285,77,who,O,WP
3286,3286,77,looked,O,VBD
3287,3287,77,terrible,O,JJ
3288,3288,77,with,O,IN
3289,3289,77,his,O,PRP$
3290,3290,77,thousand,O,CD
3291,3291,77,sharp,O,JJ
3292,3292,77,teeth,O,NNS
3293,3293,77,extending,O,VBG
3294,3294,77,over,O,IN
3295,3295,77,a,O,DT
3296,3296,77,hundred,O,CD
3297,3297,77,Yojanas,O,NNP
3298,3298,77,",",O,","
3299,3299,77,and,O,CC
3300,3300,77,had,O,VBD
3301,3301,77,four,O,CD
3302,3302,77,prominent,O,JJ
3303,3303,77,ones,O,NNS
3304,3304,77,thick-set,O,JJ
3305,3305,77,",",O,","
3306,3306,77,and,O,CC
3307,3307,77,shining,O,VBG
3308,3308,77,like,O,IN
3309,3309,77,a,O,DT
3310,3310,77,pillar,O,NN
3311,3311,77,of,O,IN
3312,3312,77,silver,O,NN
3313,3313,77,",",O,","
3314,3314,77,and,O,CC
3315,3315,77,extending,O,VBG
3316,3316,77,over,O,IN
3317,3317,77,two,O,CD
3318,3318,77,hundred,O,CD
3319,3319,77,Yojanas,O,NNPS
3320,3320,77,.,O,.
3321,3321,78,And,O,CC
3322,3322,78,when,O,WRB
3323,3323,78,grinding,O,VBG
3324,3324,78,his,O,PRP$
3325,3325,78,teeth,O,NNS
3326,3326,78,he,O,PRP
3327,3327,78,pursued,O,VBD
3328,3328,78,thee,O,PRP
3329,3329,78,with,O,IN
3330,3330,78,his,O,PRP$
3331,3331,78,terrible,O,JJ
3332,3332,78,and,O,CC
3333,3333,78,uplifted,O,JJ
3334,3334,78,pike,O,NN
3335,3335,78,with,O,IN
3336,3336,78,the,O,DT
3337,3337,78,object,O,NN
3338,3338,78,of,O,IN
3339,3339,78,killing,O,VBG
3340,3340,78,thee,O,PRP
3341,3341,78,.,O,.
3342,3342,79,Thou,O,PRP
3343,3343,79,on,O,IN
3344,3344,79,beholding,O,VBG
3345,3345,79,that,O,DT
3346,3346,79,terrible,O,JJ
3347,3347,79,monster,O,NN
3348,3348,79,",",O,","
3349,3349,79,presented,O,VBD
3350,3350,79,a,O,DT
3351,3351,79,(,O,","
3352,3352,79,pitiful,O,JJ
3353,3353,79,),O,","
3354,3354,79,spectacle,O,NN
3355,3355,79,to,O,IN
3356,3356,79,all,O,PDT
3357,3357,79,the,O,DT
3358,3358,79,by-standers,O,NNS
3359,3359,79,.,O,.
3360,3360,80,Then,O,RB
3361,3361,80,",",O,","
3362,3362,80,O,O,UH
3363,3363,80,slayer,O,NN
3364,3364,80,of,O,IN
3365,3365,80,Danavas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3366,3366,80,",",O,","
3367,3367,80,overcome,O,VBN
3368,3368,80,with,O,IN
3369,3369,80,fear,O,NN
3370,3370,80,of,O,IN
3371,3371,80,the,O,DT
3372,3372,80,monster,O,NN
3373,3373,80,",",O,","
3374,3374,80,with,O,IN
3375,3375,80,thy,O,PRP$
3376,3376,80,hands,O,NNS
3377,3377,80,clasped,O,VBN
3378,3378,80,in,O,IN
3379,3379,80,supplication,O,NN
3380,3380,80,",",O,","
3381,3381,80,thou,O,DT
3382,3382,80,didst,O,NN
3383,3383,80,seek,O,VBP
3384,3384,80,the,O,DT
3385,3385,80,protection,O,NN
3386,3386,80,of,O,IN
3387,3387,80,the,O,DT
3388,3388,80,great,O,JJ
3389,3389,80,sage,O,NN
3390,3390,80,.,O,.
3391,3391,81,The,O,DT
3392,3392,81,might,O,NN
3393,3393,81,of,O,IN
3394,3394,81,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3395,3395,81,",",O,","
3396,3396,81,O,O,NNP
3397,3397,81,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
3398,3398,81,",",O,","
3399,3399,81,is,O,VBZ
3400,3400,81,greater,O,JJR
3401,3401,81,than,O,IN
3402,3402,81,that,O,DT
3403,3403,81,of,O,IN
3404,3404,81,the,O,DT
3405,3405,81,Kshatriyas,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
3406,3406,81,.,O,.
3407,3407,82,None,O,NN
3408,3408,82,are,O,VBP
3409,3409,82,more,O,RBR
3410,3410,82,powerful,O,JJ
3411,3411,82,than,O,IN
3412,3412,82,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3413,3413,82,and,O,CC
3414,3414,82,knowing,O,VBG
3415,3415,82,duly,O,RB
3416,3416,82,",",O,","
3417,3417,82,as,O,IN
3418,3418,82,I,O,PRP
3419,3419,82,do,O,VBP
3420,3420,82,",",O,","
3421,3421,82,the,O,DT
3422,3422,82,power,O,NN
3423,3423,82,of,O,IN
3424,3424,82,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3425,3425,82,",",O,","
3426,3426,82,I,O,PRP
3427,3427,82,do,O,VBP
3428,3428,82,not,O,RB
3429,3429,82,",",O,","
3430,3430,82,O,O,UH
3431,3431,82,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
3432,3432,82,",",O,","
3433,3433,82,desire,O,VBP
3434,3434,82,to,O,TO
3435,3435,82,come,O,VB
3436,3436,82,in,O,IN
3437,3437,82,conflict,O,NN
3438,3438,82,with,O,IN
3439,3439,82,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
3440,3440,82,.,O,.
3441,3441,82,',O,''
3442,3442,82,'',O,''
3443,3443,82,',O,''
3444,3444,82,'',O,''
3445,3445,83,SECTION,O,NNP
3446,3446,83,X,O,NNP
3447,3447,83,'',O,''
3448,3448,83,',O,''
3449,3449,83,'',O,''
3450,3450,83,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3451,3451,83,said,O,VBD
3452,3452,83,",",O,","
3453,3453,83,',O,''
3454,3454,83,Even,O,RB
3455,3455,83,so,O,RB
3456,3456,83,it,O,PRP
3457,3457,83,is,O,VBZ
3458,3458,83,;,O,:
3459,3459,83,the,O,DT
3460,3460,83,might,O,NN
3461,3461,83,of,O,IN
3462,3462,83,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3463,3463,83,is,O,VBZ
3464,3464,83,great,O,JJ
3465,3465,83,and,O,CC
3466,3466,83,there,O,EX
3467,3467,83,are,O,VBP
3468,3468,83,none,O,NN
3469,3469,83,more,O,RBR
3470,3470,83,powerful,O,JJ
3471,3471,83,than,O,IN
3472,3472,83,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3473,3473,83,",",O,","
3474,3474,83,but,O,CC
3475,3475,83,I,O,PRP
3476,3476,83,can,O,MD
3477,3477,83,never,O,RB
3478,3478,83,bear,O,VB
3479,3479,83,with,O,IN
3480,3480,83,equanimity,O,NN
3481,3481,83,the,O,DT
3482,3482,83,insolent,O,JJ
3483,3483,83,pride,O,NN
3484,3484,83,of,O,IN
3485,3485,83,Avikshita,B-PER,NNP
3486,3486,83,',O,POS
3487,3487,83,s,O,POS
3488,3488,83,son,O,NN
3489,3489,83,",",O,","
3490,3490,83,and,O,CC
3491,3491,83,so,O,RB
3492,3492,83,shall,O,MD
3493,3493,83,I,O,PRP
3494,3494,83,smite,O,VB
3495,3495,83,him,O,PRP
3496,3496,83,with,O,IN
3497,3497,83,my,O,PRP$
3498,3498,83,thunderbolt,O,NN
3499,3499,83,.,O,.
3500,3500,84,Therefore,O,RB
3501,3501,84,",",O,","
3502,3502,84,O,O,UH
3503,3503,84,Dhritarashtra,B-PER,NNP
3504,3504,84,",",O,","
3505,3505,84,do,O,VB
3506,3506,84,thou,O,DT
3507,3507,84,according,O,VBG
3508,3508,84,to,O,IN
3509,3509,84,my,O,PRP$
3510,3510,84,direction,O,NN
3511,3511,84,repair,O,NN
3512,3512,84,to,O,IN
3513,3513,84,king,O,NN
3514,3514,84,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
3515,3515,84,attended,O,VBN
3516,3516,84,by,O,IN
3517,3517,84,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
3518,3518,84,",",O,","
3519,3519,84,and,O,CC
3520,3520,84,deliver,O,VB
3521,3521,84,this,O,DT
3522,3522,84,message,O,NN
3523,3523,84,to,O,IN
3524,3524,84,him,O,PRP
3525,3525,84,--,O,:
3526,3526,84,'',O,''
3527,3527,84,Do,O,VB
3528,3528,84,thou,O,PRP
3529,3529,84,",",O,","
3530,3530,84,O,O,UH
3531,3531,84,prince,O,NN
3532,3532,84,",",O,","
3533,3533,84,accept,O,VB
3534,3534,84,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
3535,3535,84,as,O,IN
3536,3536,84,thy,O,DT
3537,3537,84,spiritual,O,JJ
3538,3538,84,preceptor,O,NN
3539,3539,84,",",O,","
3540,3540,84,as,O,IN
3541,3541,84,otherwise,O,RB
3542,3542,84,",",O,","
3543,3543,84,I,O,PRP
3544,3544,84,shall,O,MD
3545,3545,84,strike,O,VB
3546,3546,84,thee,O,PRP
3547,3547,84,with,O,IN
3548,3548,84,my,O,PRP$
3549,3549,84,terrific,O,JJ
3550,3550,84,thunderbolt,O,NN
3551,3551,84,.,O,.
3552,3552,84,'',O,''
3553,3553,84,',O,''
3554,3554,84,'',O,''
3555,3555,85,``,O,``
3556,3556,85,',O,''
3557,3557,85,Vyasa,B-PER,NNP
3558,3558,85,said,O,VBD
3559,3559,85,",",O,","
3560,3560,85,``,O,``
3561,3561,85,Then,O,RB
3562,3562,85,Dhritarashtra,B-PER,NNP
3563,3563,85,betook,O,VBD
3564,3564,85,himself,O,PRP
3565,3565,85,to,O,IN
3566,3566,85,that,O,DT
3567,3567,85,monarch,O,NN
3568,3568,85,',O,''
3569,3569,85,s,O,POS
3570,3570,85,court,O,NN
3571,3571,85,and,O,CC
3572,3572,85,delivered,O,VBD
3573,3573,85,this,O,DT
3574,3574,85,message,O,NN
3575,3575,85,to,O,IN
3576,3576,85,him,O,PRP
3577,3577,85,from,O,IN
3578,3578,85,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
3579,3579,85,.,O,.
3580,3580,86,``,O,``
3581,3581,86,',O,''
3582,3582,86,'',O,''
3583,3583,86,Dhritarashtra,B-PER,NNP
3584,3584,86,said,O,VBD
3585,3585,86,",",O,","
3586,3586,86,',O,''
3587,3587,86,O,O,UH
3588,3588,86,lord,O,NN
3589,3589,86,of,O,IN
3590,3590,86,men,O,NNS
3591,3591,86,",",O,","
3592,3592,86,know,O,VB
3593,3593,86,that,O,IN
3594,3594,86,I,O,PRP
3595,3595,86,am,O,VBP
3596,3596,86,Dhritarashtra,B-PER,NNP
3597,3597,86,the,O,DT
3598,3598,86,Gandharva,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3599,3599,86,",",O,","
3600,3600,86,come,O,VBP
3601,3601,86,here,O,RB
3602,3602,86,with,O,IN
3603,3603,86,the,O,DT
3604,3604,86,object,O,NN
3605,3605,86,[,O,-LRB-
3606,3606,86,of,O,IN
3607,3607,86,],O,''
3608,3608,86,delivering,O,VBG
3609,3609,86,to,O,IN
3610,3610,86,thee,O,PRP
3611,3611,86,the,O,DT
3612,3612,86,message,O,NN
3613,3613,86,of,O,IN
3614,3614,86,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3615,3615,86,.,O,.
3616,3616,87,Do,O,VB
3617,3617,87,thou,O,PRP
3618,3618,87,",",O,","
3619,3619,87,O,O,UH
3620,3620,87,lion,O,NN
3621,3621,87,among,O,IN
3622,3622,87,kings,O,NNS
3623,3623,87,",",O,","
3624,3624,87,listen,O,VB
3625,3625,87,to,O,IN
3626,3626,87,the,O,DT
3627,3627,87,words,O,NNS
3628,3628,87,which,O,WDT
3629,3629,87,the,O,DT
3630,3630,87,high-souled,O,JJ
3631,3631,87,lord,O,NN
3632,3632,87,of,O,IN
3633,3633,87,all,O,PDT
3634,3634,87,the,O,DT
3635,3635,87,worlds,O,NNS
3636,3636,87,meant,O,VBD
3637,3637,87,for,O,IN
3638,3638,87,thee,O,PRP
3639,3639,87,",",O,","
3640,3640,87,--,O,:
3641,3641,87,That,O,IN
3642,3642,87,one,O,CD
3643,3643,87,of,O,IN
3644,3644,87,incomprehensible,O,JJ
3645,3645,87,achievements,O,NNS
3646,3646,87,(,O,-LRB-
3647,3647,87,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3648,3648,87,),O,-RRB-
3649,3649,87,only,O,RB
3650,3650,87,said,O,VBD
3651,3651,87,this,O,DT
3652,3652,87,much,O,JJ
3653,3653,87,",",O,","
3654,3654,87,``,O,``
3655,3655,87,Do,O,VBP
3656,3656,87,thou,O,PRP
3657,3657,87,accept,O,VB
3658,3658,87,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
3659,3659,87,as,O,IN
3660,3660,87,thy,O,DT
3661,3661,87,officiating,O,VBG
3662,3662,87,priest,O,NN
3663,3663,87,for,O,IN
3664,3664,87,the,O,DT
3665,3665,87,sacrifice,O,NN
3666,3666,87,",",O,","
3667,3667,87,or,O,CC
3668,3668,87,if,O,IN
3669,3669,87,thou,O,PRP
3670,3670,87,do,O,VBP
3671,3671,87,not,O,RB
3672,3672,87,comply,O,VB
3673,3673,87,with,O,IN
3674,3674,87,my,O,PRP$
3675,3675,87,request,O,NN
3676,3676,87,",",O,","
3677,3677,87,I,O,PRP
3678,3678,87,shall,O,MD
3679,3679,87,strike,O,VB
3680,3680,87,thee,O,PRP
3681,3681,87,with,O,IN
3682,3682,87,my,O,PRP$
3683,3683,87,terrific,O,JJ
3684,3684,87,thunderbolt,O,NN
3685,3685,87,.,O,.
3686,3686,87,'',O,''
3687,3687,87,',O,''
3688,3688,88,``,O,``
3689,3689,88,',O,''
3690,3690,88,'',O,''
3691,3691,88,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
3692,3692,88,said,O,VBD
3693,3693,88,",",O,","
3694,3694,88,',O,''
3695,3695,88,Thou,O,UH
3696,3696,88,",",O,","
3697,3697,88,O,O,UH
3698,3698,88,Purandara,B-PER,NNP
3699,3699,88,",",O,","
3700,3700,88,the,O,DT
3701,3701,88,Viswadevas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3702,3702,88,",",O,","
3703,3703,88,the,O,DT
3704,3704,88,Vasus,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3705,3705,88,and,O,CC
3706,3706,88,the,O,DT
3707,3707,88,Aswins,B-COMMUNITY,NNPS
3708,3708,88,ye,O,PRP
3709,3709,88,all,O,DT
3710,3710,88,know,O,VBP
3711,3711,88,",",O,","
3712,3712,88,that,O,IN
3713,3713,88,in,O,IN
3714,3714,88,this,O,DT
3715,3715,88,world,O,NN
3716,3716,88,there,O,EX
3717,3717,88,is,O,VBZ
3718,3718,88,no,O,DT
3719,3719,88,escape,O,NN
3720,3720,88,from,O,IN
3721,3721,88,the,O,DT
3722,3722,88,consequences,O,NNS
3723,3723,88,of,O,IN
3724,3724,88,playing,O,VBG
3725,3725,88,false,O,JJ
3726,3726,88,to,O,IN
3727,3727,88,a,O,DT
3728,3728,88,friend,O,NN
3729,3729,88,;,O,:
3730,3730,88,it,O,PRP
3731,3731,88,is,O,VBZ
3732,3732,88,a,O,DT
3733,3733,88,great,O,JJ
3734,3734,88,sin,O,NN
3735,3735,88,like,O,IN
3736,3736,88,unto,O,IN
3737,3737,88,that,O,DT
3738,3738,88,of,O,IN
3739,3739,88,murdering,O,VBG
3740,3740,88,a,O,DT
3741,3741,88,Brahman,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3742,3742,88,.,O,.
3743,3743,89,Let,O,VB
3744,3744,89,Vrihaspati,B-PER,NNP
3745,3745,89,(,O,-LRB-
3746,3746,89,therefore,O,RB
3747,3747,89,),O,-RRB-
3748,3748,89,officiate,O,VB
3749,3749,89,as,O,IN
3750,3750,89,priest,O,NN
3751,3751,89,to,O,IN
3752,3752,89,that,O,DT
3753,3753,89,Mahendra,B-PER,NNP
3754,3754,89,the,O,DT
3755,3755,89,supreme,O,NN
3756,3756,89,Deva,B-PER,NNP
3757,3757,89,(,O,HYPH
3758,3758,89,god,O,NNP
3759,3759,89,),O,-RRB-
3760,3760,89,",",O,","
3761,3761,89,the,O,DT
3762,3762,89,highest,O,JJS
3763,3763,89,one,O,NN
3764,3764,89,wielding,O,VBG
3765,3765,89,the,O,DT
3766,3766,89,thunderbolt,O,NN
3767,3767,89,",",O,","
3768,3768,89,and,O,CC
3769,3769,89,O,O,UH
3770,3770,89,prince,O,NN
3771,3771,89,",",O,","
3772,3772,89,Samvarta,O,NNP
3773,3773,89,will,O,MD
3774,3774,89,act,O,VB
3775,3775,89,as,O,IN
3776,3776,89,my,O,PRP$
3777,3777,89,priest,O,NN
3778,3778,89,",",O,","
3779,3779,89,as,O,IN
3780,3780,89,neither,O,CC
3781,3781,89,his,O,PRP$
3782,3782,89,(,O,","
3783,3783,89,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3784,3784,89,',O,POS
3785,3785,89,s,O,NNS
3786,3786,89,),O,-RRB-
3787,3787,89,words,O,NNS
3788,3788,89,",",O,","
3789,3789,89,nor,O,CC
3790,3790,89,thine,O,NN
3791,3791,89,commend,O,VBP
3792,3792,89,themselves,O,PRP
3793,3793,89,to,O,IN
3794,3794,89,me,O,PRP
3795,3795,89,.,O,.
3796,3796,89,',O,''
3797,3797,90,``,O,``
3798,3798,90,',O,''
3799,3799,90,'',O,''
3800,3800,90,The,O,DT
3801,3801,90,Gandharva,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3802,3802,90,said,O,VBD
3803,3803,90,",",O,","
3804,3804,90,',O,''
3805,3805,90,Do,O,VB
3806,3806,90,thou,O,PRP
3807,3807,90,",",O,","
3808,3808,90,O,O,UH
3809,3809,90,lion,O,NN
3810,3810,90,among,O,IN
3811,3811,90,princes,O,NNS
3812,3812,90,",",O,","
3813,3813,90,listen,O,VB
3814,3814,90,to,O,IN
3815,3815,90,the,O,DT
3816,3816,90,terrible,O,JJ
3817,3817,90,war-cry,O,NN
3818,3818,90,of,O,IN
3819,3819,90,Vasava,O,NNP
3820,3820,90,roaring,O,VBG
3821,3821,90,",",O,","
3822,3822,90,in,O,IN
3823,3823,90,the,O,DT
3824,3824,90,heavens,O,NNPS
3825,3825,90,.,O,.
3826,3826,91,Assuredly,O,RB
3827,3827,91,",",O,","
3828,3828,91,and,O,CC
3829,3829,91,openly,O,RB
3830,3830,91,will,O,MD
3831,3831,91,Mahendra,B-PER,NNP
3832,3832,91,hurl,O,VB
3833,3833,91,his,O,PRP$
3834,3834,91,thunderbolt,O,NN
3835,3835,91,at,O,IN
3836,3836,91,thee,O,PRP
3837,3837,91,.,O,.
3838,3838,92,Do,O,VB
3839,3839,92,thou,O,DT
3840,3840,92,therefore,O,RB
3841,3841,92,be-think,O,VB
3842,3842,92,thyself,O,PRP
3843,3843,92,of,O,IN
3844,3844,92,thy,O,DT
3845,3845,92,good,O,NN
3846,3846,92,",",O,","
3847,3847,92,for,O,IN
3848,3848,92,this,O,DT
3849,3849,92,is,O,VBZ
3850,3850,92,the,O,DT
3851,3851,92,time,O,NN
3852,3852,92,to,O,TO
3853,3853,92,do,O,VB
3854,3854,92,it,O,PRP
3855,3855,92,.,O,.
3856,3856,92,',O,''
3857,3857,92,'',O,''
3858,3858,93,``,O,``
3859,3859,93,',O,''
3860,3860,93,Vyasa,B-PER,NNP
3861,3861,93,said,O,VBD
3862,3862,93,",",O,","
3863,3863,93,``,O,``
3864,3864,93,Thus,O,RB
3865,3865,93,accosted,O,VBN
3866,3866,93,by,O,IN
3867,3867,93,Dhritarashtra,B-PER,NNP
3868,3868,93,",",O,","
3869,3869,93,and,O,CC
3870,3870,93,hearing,O,VBG
3871,3871,93,the,O,DT
3872,3872,93,roar,O,NN
3873,3873,93,of,O,IN
3874,3874,93,howling,O,VBG
3875,3875,93,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
3876,3876,93,",",O,","
3877,3877,93,the,O,DT
3878,3878,93,king,O,NN
3879,3879,93,communicated,O,VBD
3880,3880,93,this,O,DT
3881,3881,93,intelligence,O,NN
3882,3882,93,to,O,IN
3883,3883,93,Samvarta,B-PLACE,NNP
3884,3884,93,steadfast,O,JJ
3885,3885,93,in,O,IN
3886,3886,93,devotion,O,NN
3887,3887,93,and,O,CC
3888,3888,93,the,O,DT
3889,3889,93,highest,O,JJS
3890,3890,93,of,O,IN
3891,3891,93,all,O,DT
3892,3892,93,virtuous,O,JJ
3893,3893,93,men,O,NNS
3894,3894,93,.,O,.
3895,3895,94,``,O,``
3896,3896,94,',O,''
3897,3897,94,'',O,''
3898,3898,94,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
3899,3899,94,said,O,VBD
3900,3900,94,",",O,","
3901,3901,94,',O,''
3902,3902,94,Verily,O,RB
3903,3903,94,this,O,DT
3904,3904,94,rain-cloud,O,NN
3905,3905,94,floating,O,VBG
3906,3906,94,in,O,IN
3907,3907,94,the,O,DT
3908,3908,94,air,O,NN
3909,3909,94,indicates,O,VBZ
3910,3910,94,that,O,IN
3911,3911,94,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3912,3912,94,must,O,MD
3913,3913,94,be,O,VB
3914,3914,94,near,O,IN
3915,3915,94,at,O,IN
3916,3916,94,present,O,NN
3917,3917,94,",",O,","
3918,3918,94,therefore,O,RB
3919,3919,94,",",O,","
3920,3920,94,O,O,UH
3921,3921,94,prince,O,NN
3922,3922,94,of,O,IN
3923,3923,94,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3924,3924,94,",",O,","
3925,3925,94,I,O,PRP
3926,3926,94,seek,O,VBP
3927,3927,94,shelter,O,NN
3928,3928,94,from,O,IN
3929,3929,94,thee,O,PRP
3930,3930,94,.,O,.
3931,3931,95,Do,O,VB
3932,3932,95,thou,O,PRP
3933,3933,95,",",O,","
3934,3934,95,O,O,UH
3935,3935,95,best,O,JJS
3936,3936,95,of,O,IN
3937,3937,95,Brahmanas,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
3938,3938,95,",",O,","
3939,3939,95,remove,O,VB
3940,3940,95,this,O,DT
3941,3941,95,fear,O,NN
3942,3942,95,of,O,IN
3943,3943,95,Indra,B-PER,NNP
3944,3944,95,from,O,IN
3945,3945,95,my,O,PRP$
3946,3946,95,mind,O,NN
3947,3947,95,.,O,.
3948,3948,96,The,O,DT
3949,3949,96,Wielder,O,NNP
3950,3950,96,of,O,IN
3951,3951,96,the,O,DT
3952,3952,96,thunderbolt,O,NN
3953,3953,96,is,O,VBZ
3954,3954,96,coming,O,VBG
3955,3955,96,encompassing,O,VBG
3956,3956,96,the,O,DT
3957,3957,96,ten,O,CD
3958,3958,96,directions,O,NNS
3959,3959,96,of,O,IN
3960,3960,96,space,O,NN
3961,3961,96,with,O,IN
3962,3962,96,his,O,PRP$
3963,3963,96,terrible,O,JJ
3964,3964,96,and,O,CC
3965,3965,96,superhuman,O,JJ
3966,3966,96,refulgence,O,NN
3967,3967,96,and,O,CC
3968,3968,96,my,O,PRP$
3969,3969,96,assistants,O,NNS
3970,3970,96,at,O,IN
3971,3971,96,this,O,DT
3972,3972,96,sacrificial,O,JJ
3973,3973,96,assembly,O,NN
3974,3974,96,have,O,VBP
3975,3975,96,been,O,VBN
3976,3976,96,overcome,O,VBN
3977,3977,96,with,O,IN
3978,3978,96,fright,O,NN
3979,3979,96,.,O,.
3980,3980,96,',O,''
3981,3981,97,``,O,``
3982,3982,97,',O,''
3983,3983,97,'',O,''
3984,3984,97,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
3985,3985,97,said,O,VBD
3986,3986,97,",",O,","
3987,3987,97,',O,''
3988,3988,97,O,O,UH
3989,3989,97,lion,O,NN
3990,3990,97,among,O,IN
3991,3991,97,kings,O,NNS
3992,3992,97,",",O,","
3993,3993,97,thy,O,PRP$
3994,3994,97,fear,O,NN
3995,3995,97,of,O,IN
3996,3996,97,Sakra,B-PER,NNP
3997,3997,97,will,O,MD
3998,3998,97,soon,O,RB
3999,3999,97,be,O,VB
4000,4000,97,dispelled,O,VBN
4001,4001,97,",",O,","
4002,4002,97,and,O,CC
4003,4003,97,I,O,PRP
4004,4004,97,shall,O,MD
4005,4005,97,soon,O,RB
4006,4006,97,remove,O,VB
4007,4007,97,this,O,DT
4008,4008,97,terrible,O,JJ
4009,4009,97,pain,O,NN
4010,4010,97,by,O,IN
4011,4011,97,means,O,NNS
4012,4012,97,of,O,IN
4013,4013,97,my,O,PRP$
4014,4014,97,magic,O,JJ
4015,4015,97,lore,O,NN
4016,4016,97,(,O,","
4017,4017,97,incantation,O,NN
4018,4018,97,),O,-RRB-
4019,4019,97,;,O,:
4020,4020,97,be,O,VB
4021,4021,97,calm,O,JJ
4022,4022,97,and,O,CC
4023,4023,97,have,O,VB
4024,4024,97,no,O,DT
4025,4025,97,fear,O,NN
4026,4026,97,of,O,IN
4027,4027,97,being,O,VBG
4028,4028,97,overpowered,O,VBN
4029,4029,97,by,O,IN
4030,4030,97,Indra,B-PER,NNP
4031,4031,97,.,O,.
4032,4032,98,Thou,O,PRP
4033,4033,98,hast,O,VBP
4034,4034,98,nothing,O,NN
4035,4035,98,to,O,TO
4036,4036,98,fear,O,VB
4037,4037,98,from,O,IN
4038,4038,98,the,O,DT
4039,4039,98,god,O,NN
4040,4040,98,of,O,IN
4041,4041,98,a,O,DT
4042,4042,98,hundred,O,CD
4043,4043,98,sacrifices,O,NNS
4044,4044,98,.,O,.
4045,4045,99,I,O,PRP
4046,4046,99,shall,O,MD
4047,4047,99,use,O,VB
4048,4048,99,my,O,PRP$
4049,4049,99,staying,O,NN
4050,4050,99,charms,O,NNS
4051,4051,99,",",O,","
4052,4052,99,O,O,UH
4053,4053,99,king,O,NN
4054,4054,99,",",O,","
4055,4055,99,and,O,CC
4056,4056,99,the,O,DT
4057,4057,99,weapons,O,NNS
4058,4058,99,of,O,IN
4059,4059,99,all,O,PDT
4060,4060,99,the,O,DT
4061,4061,99,gods,O,NNS
4062,4062,99,will,O,MD
4063,4063,99,avail,O,VB
4064,4064,99,them,O,PRP
4065,4065,99,not,O,RB
4066,4066,99,.,O,.
4067,4067,100,Let,O,VB
4068,4068,100,the,O,DT
4069,4069,100,lightening,O,NN
4070,4070,100,flash,O,VB
4071,4071,100,in,O,IN
4072,4072,100,all,O,PDT
4073,4073,100,the,O,DT
4074,4074,100,directions,O,NNS
4075,4075,100,of,O,IN
4076,4076,100,space,O,NN
4077,4077,100,",",O,","
4078,4078,100,and,O,CC
4079,4079,100,the,O,DT
4080,4080,100,winds,O,NNS
4081,4081,100,entering,O,VBG
4082,4082,100,into,O,IN
4083,4083,100,the,O,DT
4084,4084,100,clouds,O,NNS
4085,4085,100,pour,O,VBP
4086,4086,100,down,O,RP
4087,4087,100,the,O,DT
4088,4088,100,showers,O,NNS
4089,4089,100,amid,O,IN
4090,4090,100,the,O,DT
4091,4091,100,forests,O,NNS
4092,4092,100,and,O,CC
4093,4093,100,the,O,DT
4094,4094,100,waters,O,NNS
4095,4095,100,deluge,O,VBP
4096,4096,100,the,O,DT
4097,4097,100,heavens,O,NNS
4098,4098,100,and,O,CC
4099,4099,100,the,O,DT
4100,4100,100,flashes,O,NNS
4101,4101,100,of,O,IN
4102,4102,100,lightning,O,NN
4103,4103,100,that,O,WDT
4104,4104,100,are,O,VBP
4105,4105,100,seen,O,VBN
4106,4106,100,will,O,MD
4107,4107,100,avail,O,VB
4108,4108,100,not,O,RB
4109,4109,100,.,O,.
4110,4110,101,Thou,O,PRP
4111,4111,101,hast,O,VBP
4112,4112,101,nothing,O,NN
4113,4113,101,to,O,TO
4114,4114,101,fear,O,VB
4115,4115,101,",",O,","
4116,4116,101,let,O,VB
4117,4117,101,Vasava,B-PER,NNP
4118,4118,101,pour,O,VB
4119,4119,101,down,O,RP
4120,4120,101,the,O,DT
4121,4121,101,rains,O,NNS
4122,4122,101,and,O,CC
4123,4123,101,blast,O,VB
4124,4124,101,his,O,PRP$
4125,4125,101,terrific,O,JJ
4126,4126,101,thunderbolt,O,NN
4127,4127,101,where,O,WRB
4128,4128,101,he,O,PRP
4129,4129,101,will,O,MD
4130,4130,101,",",O,","
4131,4131,101,floating,O,VBG
4132,4132,101,among,O,IN
4133,4133,101,the,O,DT
4134,4134,101,watery,O,JJ
4135,4135,101,masses,O,NNS
4136,4136,101,(,O,","
4137,4137,101,clouds,O,NNS
4138,4138,101,),O,","
4139,4139,101,for,O,IN
4140,4140,101,thy,O,DT
4141,4141,101,destruction,O,NN
4142,4142,101,",",O,","
4143,4143,101,for,O,IN
4144,4144,101,the,O,DT
4145,4145,101,god,O,NN
4146,4146,101,Vahnni,O,NNP
4147,4147,101,(,O,-LRB-
4148,4148,101,Agni,B-PER,NNP
4149,4149,101,),O,-RRB-
4150,4150,101,will,O,MD
4151,4151,101,protect,O,VB
4152,4152,101,thee,O,PRP
4153,4153,101,in,O,IN
4154,4154,101,every,O,DT
4155,4155,101,way,O,NN
4156,4156,101,",",O,","
4157,4157,101,and,O,CC
4158,4158,101,make,O,VB
4159,4159,101,thee,O,PRP
4160,4160,101,attain,O,VB
4161,4161,101,all,O,PDT
4162,4162,101,the,O,DT
4163,4163,101,objects,O,NNS
4164,4164,101,of,O,IN
4165,4165,101,thy,O,DT
4166,4166,101,desire,O,NN
4167,4167,101,.,O,.
4168,4168,101,',O,''
4169,4169,102,``,O,``
4170,4170,102,',O,''
4171,4171,102,'',O,''
4172,4172,102,Marutta,B-PER,NNP
4173,4173,102,said,O,VBD
4174,4174,102,",",O,","
4175,4175,102,',O,''
4176,4176,102,This,O,DT
4177,4177,102,appalling,O,JJ
4178,4178,102,crash,O,NN
4179,4179,102,of,O,IN
4180,4180,102,the,O,DT
4181,4181,102,thunderbolt,O,NN
4182,4182,102,together,O,RB
4183,4183,102,with,O,IN
4184,4184,102,the,O,DT
4185,4185,102,howling,O,NN
4186,4186,102,of,O,IN
4187,4187,102,the,O,DT
4188,4188,102,winds,O,NNS
4189,4189,102,",",O,","
4190,4190,102,seem,O,VBP
4191,4191,102,terrible,O,JJ
4192,4192,102,to,O,IN
4193,4193,102,my,O,PRP$
4194,4194,102,ears,O,NNS
4195,4195,102,and,O,CC
4196,4196,102,my,O,PRP$
4197,4197,102,heart,O,NN
4198,4198,102,is,O,VBZ
4199,4199,102,afflicted,O,JJ
4200,4200,102,again,O,RB
4201,4201,102,and,O,CC
4202,4202,102,again,O,RB
4203,4203,102,",",O,","
4204,4204,102,O,O,UH
4205,4205,102,Brahmana,B-COMMUNITY,NNP
4206,4206,102,",",O,","
4207,4207,102,and,O,CC
4208,4208,102,my,O,PRP$
4209,4209,102,peace,O,NN
4210,4210,102,of,O,IN
4211,4211,102,mind,O,NN
4212,4212,102,is,O,VBZ
4213,4213,102,gone,O,VBN
4214,4214,102,at,O,IN
4215,4215,102,present,O,NN
4216,4216,102,.,O,.
4217,4217,102,',O,''
4218,4218,103,``,O,``
4219,4219,103,',O,''
4220,4220,103,'',O,''
4221,4221,103,Samvarta,B-PER,NNP
4222,4222,103,said,O,VBD
4223,4223,103,",",O,","
4224,4224,103,',O,''
4225,4225,103,O,O,UH
4226,4226,103,king,O,NN
4227,4227,103,",",O,","
4228,4228,103,the,O,DT
4229,4229,103,fear,O,NN
4230,4230,103,in,O,IN
4231,4231,103,thy,O,DT
4232,4232,103,mind,O,NN
4233,4233,103,from,O,IN
4234,4234,103,this,O,DT
4235,4235,103,terrible,O,JJ
4236,4236,103,thunderbolt,O,NN
4237,4237,103,will,O,MD
4238,4238,103,leave,O,VB
4239,4239,103,thee,O,PRP
4240,4240,103,presently,O,RB
4241,4241,103,.,O,.
4242,4242,104,I,O,PRP
4243,4243,104,shall,O,MD
4244,4244,104,dispel,O,VB
4245,4245,104,the,O,DT
4246,4246,104,thunder,O,NN
4247,4247,104,by,O,IN
4248,4248,104,the,O,DT
4249,4249,104,aid,O,NN
4250,4250,104,of,O,IN
4251,4251,104,the,O,DT
4252,4252,104,winds,O,NNS
4253,4253,104,",",O,","
4254,4254,104,and,O,CC
4255,4255,104,setting,O,VBG
4256,4256,104,aside,O,RB
4257,4257,104,all,O,DT
4258,4258,104,fear,O,NN
4259,4259,104,from,O,IN
4260,4260,104,thy,O,DT
4261,4261,104,mind,O,NN
4262,4262,104,",",O,","
4263,4263,104,do,O,VB
4264,4264,104,thou,O,PRP
4265,4265,104,accept,O,VB
4266,4266,104,a,O,DT
4267,4267,104,boon,O,NN
4268,4268,104,from,O,IN
4269,4269,104,me,O,PRP
4270,4270,104,according,O,VBG
4271,4271,104,to,O,IN
4272,4272,104,thy,O,DT
4273,4273,104,heart,O,NN
4274,4274,104,',O,''
4275,4275,104,s,O,''
